马库斯・胡克斯和正拳组和带来第6张专辑
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal, take 6.
-应该报三个人的名字  -你要我来唱主旋律吗
- That's three names. - You want me to sing the main line?
好啦  开唱吧  开唱吧
Oh, yeah, here we go, here we go.
今晚我们将踏上南下的音乐之旅
Tonight we take a musical journey south,
传奇灵魂乐乐队马库斯・胡克斯和正拳组合
where the legendary soul band Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal
就是在那里练就了他们的标志性嗓音
developed their signature sound.
1  2
1, 2!
开始的时候  3人只是
They started out singing for pennies
在孟菲斯的市井卖唱
On the street corners of Memphis.
片名  灵魂歌手
拉拉绳
Pull the string
我就向你眨眨眼
And I'll wink at you
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我会逗你笑
I'll do funny things
如果你想要
If you want me to
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我是你的
I'm yours
永远被你操纵
To have and to hold
亲爱的  你能全权操控我这个小木偶
Darling, you've got full control of your puppet
但到了1972年
But by 1972,
马库斯・胡克斯和正拳组合
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal
已经成为蓝调音乐界的领军乐队
had become one of the biggest R&B acts in the world.
只有甜蜜灵魂乐
Nothin' like sweet soul music
让我们同聚首
To bring us together
他们在全球的演唱会票房都很火爆
They played to sellout houses all over the world.
卖出600万张唱片
They'd sold 6 million records
同时他们影响了一代美国乐坛
and influenced a generation of American musicians.
伴着甜蜜灵魂乐翩翩起舞
Dance to the sweet soul music
但这一切在1977年7月24日终结
But that all ended on July 24, 1977,
因为马库斯・胡克斯在纽约麦迪逊花园
when Marcus Hooks began his solo career
举办了一场激动人心的演唱会
with a dramatic concert
宣告自己单飞
at New York's Madison Square Garden.
女士们   先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎马库思・胡克斯
Marcus Hooks.
正当胡克斯在乐坛叱咤风云之时
But while Hooks became a music legend,
乐队的另两个成员弗洛伊德・亨德森和
the journey took a decidedly different direction
路易斯・海因兹毅然改变了曲风
for former band mates Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds.
他们凭借《公园漫步》一曲成名
Renowned for their signature dance stylings
其独特的舞步风格让他们备受赞誉
from their one breakout hit, "Walk in the Park,"
但是二人于1979年分道扬镳
the duo broke up in 1979.
据说是因为创作意见分歧
Citing creative differences
并且各自奔向自己的前程
and a desire to pursue separate projects.
退后  不许动
Back off! Freeze!
举起手  让我看见你的手
Get your hands up! Let me see them!
等等  等等  这不是...
Oh. Wait. Wait, wait. It ain't... Ohh!
枪是假的  不是真枪
The gun ain't real! Ow! It ain't real! Ow!
最新消息  正拳乐队成员路易斯・海因兹被捕
我只是没钱了  见鬼
I'm just broke, God it!
我没想伤害谁
I ain't tryin' to hurt no!
小心你的爪子
Watch your damn hands!
警察真他妈的残忍
Police mother brutality!
而另一位弗洛伊德・亨德森
While Floyd Henderson...
欢迎光临弗洛伊德洗车服务公司
Come on down to Floyd's Car Wash,
您的爱车全部享受手工擦洗服务
where everything is done by hand.
他将其出色的表演
...combined his showmanship
同商业头脑相结合
with an entrepreneur spirit.
别忘了"销魂星期日"哦
And don't forget about Super Soul Sundays,
整车清洗
with a full body wash
外带免费清洗轮胎
to guarantee a free rimjob.
来吧  免费洗轮胎
Come on. Get your rimjob.
快来免费洗轮胎
Come get your rimjob.
Come and get your rimjob!
被人遗忘的正拳组合亨德森和
Whatever happened to the forgotten duo Henderson and Hinds
海因兹究竟都遭遇了什么呢
The Real Deal?
宝贝  把导航仪打开
Baby, turn the navigation on.
希望在天黑前能到地方
I hope we can find this place sometime tonight.
他会爱上那儿的
He gonna love it there.
那里有坎麦可调床
They got Craftmatic adjustable beds,
声控灯
clap-on lamps.
跟你们说过了  最好安静点
Y'all better shut up back there, I'm tellin' you.
我真想把手伸到后座上
I'm gonna reach back there
把一个小崽子倒拎起来揍一顿
and pop one of them little boys upside the head so bad.
弗洛伊德叔叔  我想这就是我们要的
I think that's it, Uncle Floyd.
真不敢相信我竟然任你埋怨
Now, I can't believe I let you talk me into this bullshit.
你想说什么  这多美啊  你不喜欢吗
What you talking about? It's beautiful. You don't like this?
这就是一死气沉沉的营地
It's a death camp.
叔叔  它怎么就是死气沉沉的营地啦
Oh, how is it a death camp, Unc?
这里有36个洞高尔夫场地
We got 36 holes of golf.
3个游泳池
Three swimming pools.
这地方的男女比例
You know the ratio of women to men here
是1比5  叔叔  1比5啊
is 5 to 1, Unc? 5 to 1.
意思是这的小妞儿一大片
That mean you got 'em everywhere.
挤得你都动不了  到处是小妞儿...
You can't even move. There's women...
随便看一圈
Every time you look around,
身边到处都是妞儿
women crawling between your legs, arms, anything.
见鬼  叔叔  如果你担心生意的话
I mean, damn, Unc. And if you're worried about the business,
我来搞定
I got that.
你那套我都学会了
You taught me everything you know.
是啊
Yeah.
行啊  我告诉你  小子
Yeah. You know something, son?
你真够狡猾的
You're real crafty.
多谢夸奖
Appreciate that.
第一步  你搬进我家
See, first you move into my house.
然后  你抢走我的生意
Then you take over my business.
-伙计  我没有抢走  -对了  还有
- Aw, man, I ain't taking...  - Oh, yeah.
伙计  再然后  你想尽办法骗我到这个山谷来
Then you move me all the way out to the Valley, man,
就没人听到我尖叫了  对不
so can't nobody hear me scream. Right?
实际上  这就是为啥把你弄到这来
Actually, that's why we're moving you here.
在这里护士才能听见你的驴叫
So the nurses can hear your ass scream.
还记得你摔倒在地板上躺了三天吗
You remember you fell on that floor for three days
-没人听见你求救  -我记得
- and couldn't nobody hear you. - I remember.
那就行了  别抱怨啦  享受人生吧  叔叔
Yeah. Now, stop being bitter, man. Enjoy yourself, Unc.
你的黄金时代到来了  伙计
There are your golden years, player.
来吧  进屋里来
Now, come on in the house and say bye
和沙琳还有孩子们告别
to Charlene and the kids.
见鬼的小崽子
Fuck them kids.
Fuck the kids?
就是
Yeah.
就这样  宝贝儿
Ohhh... yeah, baby.
快给我  快  快点
Ohh! Oh, give it to me. Give it to me nice and hard.
就是这样
Oh, right there!
宝贝  别停
Ooh. Don't stop, baby.
不  你不能跑
No, you're not getting away.
真爽
Yummy!
髋关节感觉怎样
How's the hip?
还行
Fine.
那就好
Okay.
好了  亨德森先生
Okay, Mr. Henderson.
请站起来  面向窗户
I'm gonna need you to, uh, stands up, face the window,
趴在桌子上
and bend over the table.
大夫  我的病跟屁股没关系
My problem ain't back in that area, doctor.
亨德森先生  你的睡眠问题
Look, Mr. Henderson, your sleep problem
可能是多种原因引起的
can be a symptom of a myriad of different conditions,
其中之一  就是
some of which, you know, are...
您的屁股
well, you know, back in that area.
我讨厌有人像同性性交那样在我后面
I don't like nobody behind me like that, Huds.
告诉你  我不喜欢有人捅我的
I'm telling you, I just don't like nobody playing
-屁股眼  -我会很轻很轻的
- with my penny. - I'll be very gentle.
您不会有多大感觉的
I'll be in and out before you know it.
趴那儿  对了
Just bend over. There you go.
抓住  抓紧啦
Hold on, now. Get a good grip.
放松
Just relax.
Relax.
坐在海边码头上
Sittin' on the dock of the bay
看海...潮
Watching the tiiiiiide
潮...起...潮...落
Roll away
好了  亨德森先生  再说一次
All right, again, Mr. Henderson,
您身体绝对没问题
there's absolutely nothing wrong with you.
吃点治疗失眠的药就行
So take those for insomnia.
再有问题给我打电话  好吗
Give me a call if anything changes. All right?
-好的  -帮帮忙
- All right.  - Do me a favor.
别太勉强自己了  亨德森先生
Stop being so hard on yourself, Mr. Henderson.
退休是一种痛苦的人生转变
Retirement can be a tough transition.
对不
All right?
好啦  对了  记住
Okay. Oh, yeah. Hey, listen.
不要用酒喂药
Don't mix those sleeping pills with alcohol
除非你想自杀
unless you want to kill yourself.
行了  下一个
Okay. Who's next?
南部地区
And for those of you in the Southland,
明天是阳光明媚
tomorrow's gonna be another beautiful day with
的美好一日
bright, sunny skies
温度在85华氏度左右
and temperatures into the mid-80s.
打高尔夫球的好天气
A perfect day for some golf.
并且晴朗天气将一直持续到下周
And that's gonna continue right into next week.
晴空暖阳
Gorgeous blue skies and sensationally warm.
再惬意不过了
It doesn't get any better than that.
插播新闻
This just in.
全球的灵魂乐迷聚集起来
Soul music fans around the globe
悼念马库斯・胡克斯
are mourning the loss of Marcus Hooks.
这位传奇的歌手兼曲作者
The legendary singer and songwriter
因心脏病突发去世
apparently suffered a massive heart attack
病发时正在座无虚席的瑞典斯德哥尔摩
while performing last night in front of a capacity crowd
昆斯坦丁体育场做告别演唱
at Kungstrardgarden Park in Stockholm, Sweden.
他的遗体将运回纽约家中
His body's being flown home to New York,
下周将举行告别仪式
where a memorial service will be held next week.
这位7届格莱美奖的获得者
The seven-time Grammy Award winner
享年63岁
was 63 years old.
我愿为你做任何事情
I'll do anything for you
稍后请继续收看
We're back in just a moment.
克在因修车厂  什么事
Kezian Motors. Can I help you?
找谁
Who?
海因兹  你的电话
Hinds, telephone!
你小子是不在外面搞毒品买卖
Dealing drugs out of my garage?
听着  你要是敢干犯法的事
Listen, you doing something illegal,
让我发现了  就把你踢回监狱去
I'll find out and send your ass back to prison
所以他妈的快点讲电话
so fucking fast,
这会让你满是铜臭的黑脑袋瓜晕掉
it will make your black monkey head spin.
要是以前  你这样和我说胡话
You know, there was a time
我就敲碎你的牙
I would've knocked your teeth down your throat
让你咽下去
for saying some shit like that to me.
但是现在我改过自新了
But I'm a changed man.
一心一意做现在这些烂事
I'm trying to be all centered and shit.
我可以把你叫作
Now, I could called you
长着一条眉毛混饭吃的大屁股杂种
a unibrow-shaving, pilaf-eating, greasy-ass goat fucker,
但我没那么说  是吧
But I didn't, did I?
因为我不想伤你的感情
'Cause I didn't want to hurt your feelings,
也不想惹你生气
and I didn't want to piss you off,
正如我内心深处非常明白
just like I know deep, deep down inside,
你也不想惹我生气
you don't want to piss me off, either.
你说呢
Now, do you?
是的
Uh-uh. No. Uh-uh.
好啦
All right.
我们和好
Peace.
是  我是路易斯
Yeah, this is Louis.
您好  海因兹先生
Hey. Mr. Hinds.
我是丹尼・爱普斯坦  我在纽约  您还好吗
It's Danny Epstein calling from New York. How are you today?
你是
Who?
马蒂的儿子
Marty's son.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
靠
Shit,
我上次见你  你还戴尿布呢
I ain't seen you since you were in diapers.
是啊
Yeah. Well,
我想您已经听说
I assume you heard
马库斯去世了吧
about Marcus' passing, yeah?
恩  我在心里默默流泪来的
Oh, yeah. I'm crying the tears of a motherfucking clown.
好了  事情是这样
Okay. Here's the thing.
VH1台想在阿波罗举办一场告别演出
VH1 is putting together a farewell tribute at the Apollo,
并列了一份重要人物的出场名单
and they got a lot of big names lined up.
他们想让亨德森和海因兹表演  是吗
And they want Henderson and Hinds to perform, right?
正确  正拳组合再聚首
That's right! The Real Deal back together again.
是个大好机会
It's a great opportunity.
你和弗洛伊德说了吗
You talk to Floyd?
说了
I did.
亨德森先生同意参加
Mr. Henderson is in.
很好
Good.
可我不参加
Then I'm out.
始于坏时迹
Born under a bad sign
我从井底向上爬
Been down since I began to crawl
实在不是运气坏
If it wasn't for bad luck
我就从来不走运阿
You know I wouldn't have no luck at all
命运多坎坷...
Hard luck and trouble...
真恶心
That is disgusting.
难以置信
I don't believe this. Hmm.
见鬼
Ohh. Damn!
伙计  你他妈的干什么
Ooh. Fuck happened, man?
鬼才知道  我进来  看见你在那儿
Hell if I know. I came in, found your ass laying there.
胡说  你直勾勾地盯着我
Bullshit. You looked me dead in my eyes.
伙计  你早就认出我了
Man, you recognized me.
我没认出来  你变了好多
I didn't recognize you. You done changed.
我一路赶来
I come all the way down here,
可老兄你就瞅我一眼
and, man, you gonna look me in my face
-给我一拳  -你该事先打电话的
- and knock me the fuck out? - Should've called first.
我咋打电话
How the hell I'm gonna call
你都没电话
and you ain't got no phone?
啥样的人没有电话
What kind of person ain't got no land phone?
不想接电话的人
Kind of person don't want to get no calls.
你甚至都不问问
You don't even know why I came down
我来这破地方干啥
to this old fucked-up-the-ass neighborhood.
我知道你来干啥  小爱普跟我说了
I talked to little Ep. I know why you're here.
我的回答是不
And the answer is no.
他说了演出是在阿波罗并且票都卖光了吗
Did he tell you we're at the Apollo and they sold out?
跟你说其他的出场的名人了吗
Did he also tell you who gonna be there?
布克・T・琼斯  艾萨克・海耶斯  布特西・柯林斯
Booker T. Jones. Isaac Hayes. Bootsy Collins.
还有莎奇拉
Shakira.
关我屁事
I don't care.
就算为马库斯
Do it for Marcus.
去他妈的马库斯
Fuck Marcus.
好吧  那就为了我
Well, do it for me.
-去你妈的  -别这样  伙计
- Fuck you!  - Come on, man.
-这是我们的机会  -啥机会
- This is our shot.  - At what?
复出啊  傻瓜  我们做好了的话
At a comeback, fool. If we do this shit right,
就能拿到唱片合约  再征歌坛
we can get a record deal and get back on the road
像30年前的那样
like we was 30 years ago.
我可不想像30年前那样
I ain't trying to be like 30 years ago!
我也不想复出
I ain't trying to make no comeback.
我离开了  就不想回去
I'm gone, and I want to stay gone.
伙计  你想让我求你吗
Don't make me beg you, man.
老子曰  "故常无欲以观其妙"
Lao-Tzu says, "Free from desire, you realize the mystery."
"常有欲以观其徼"
"Caught in desire, you see only the manifestations. "
这他妈的啥意思  伙计
What the fuck that even mean, man?
意思就是
That means...
你他妈的给我滚出去
get the fuck out.
我猜你没想到可以赚到钱吧
Well, I guess you don't give a fuck about the money, huh?
赚什么钱  那是个葬礼
What money? It's a funeral!
葬礼上唱歌是没钱赚的
Nobody get paid to sing at no damn funeral!
能赚多少
How much?
4万块
40 grand.
每个人吗
A piece?
不  两人分
No, down the middle.
不不不  不不不
No, no, no, no, no, No, no, no, no!
那没多少
That ain't even enough.
伙计  没多少是什么意思
What the fuck you mean that's not enough, man?
我还是喜欢这里的生活方式
I got a lifestyle to maintain here.
伙计  这是什么生活方式
What kind of lifestyle, man,
你腰缠万贯吗
you filthy motherfucker?
满柜子都是狗粮  可我没看见狗
You got a pantry full of dog food. I don't see no dog.
狗在床底下  黑鬼
Dog under the bed, nigger! You lucky
你进门  狗没咬你屁股算你走运
he ain't attacked your ass when you came in.
你就是那条狗  混蛋
You're the dog, motherfucker!
你的存款都干什么用了  伙计
What happened to all that fucking money you done saved, man?
存款  放屁
Saved? Shit.
从水门事件那时开始直到
I don't remember shit from Watergate
航天飞机爆炸
to when the space shuttle blew up.
我就不记得有存款
Hmm. Money I saved.
好吧  还有歌曲的版税呢
Okay, what about the royalties?
我曾经每年能得到3万块呢
I used to get over $30,000 a year off that shit.
我赌扑克输了我的那份  行了吧
I lost my royalties in a poker game. All right?
-扑克  -你听好  伙计
- Poker? - Listen here, man.
如果你真想让我
If you serious about un-assing me
再度出山
from my lavish surroundings here,
伙计  你得考虑
man, you gonna have to be a little more flexible
小让一步  就...
in your thinking. Say, oh...
我6你4吧
60/40.
伙计  你可真是混帐加三级
Man, you must be higher than a motherfucker.
我们一直对半分的
We always split shit straight down the middle.
如果我不去演出
Ain't gonna be nothing to split
你连分都没啥可分的  是吧
if I don't show up, now, is there?
分不到6成  我就不去
And I ain't showing up unless I get 60% of the proceeds.
反正你有钱  混帐东西
You rich anyway, motherfucker.
我在电视上看过的你洗车广告了
I seen your little car wash commercials on the TV.
我已经把所有的生意都转给我外甥了
I transferred all my business affairs over to my nephew.
-我现在靠固定收入  伙计  -那又怎样
- I'm on a fixed income, man. - So what?
那就是中大奖了
So your draws!
所以现在2万元对我来说
That's why that 20 damn thousand dollars
-很有吸引力  -是一万六
- look good to me right now.- 16!
六四分成后你该得的那份
That's your cut of a 60/40 split.
这就是我的条件
And those are my terms.
而且没有商量的余地
And they're non-negotiable.
55/45
55/45.
去你大爷的
Fatherfuck you, man.
你要我六四分
You're gonna tell me 60/40.
你有什么资格命令我
You don't dictate to me!
我是他妈的弗洛伊德・亨德森
I'm Floyd motherfucking Henderson.
你和马库斯  都是我
You and Marc, I made you
造就了你和那个混蛋
and that motherfucker!
你不会唱歌  不会发鼻音  不会他妈的跳音
You can't sing, hum,or motherfucking skip.
我说得不对吗
Ain't that a bitch?
都他妈的见鬼去吧
Skip on these motherfucking nuts!
希望你和马库斯都下地狱
You and Marcus, may you rest in shit.
混蛋  我是弗洛伊德・亨德森
Motherfucker.I'm Floyd fucking Henderson,
你这个道貌岸然的混蛋
you Apostle-faced motherfucker!
这个混蛋又冲我摔门
This motherfucker slams this door in my face one more time...
我烦透这个混蛋了
I'm tired of this motherfucker!
总是和这个混蛋过不去
Always had a problem with this bitch.
他啥都不是  一无所知
He ain't nothing. He's ignorant!
一个混蛋白痴
Motherfucker's just a idiot.
头脑简单的混球  整天无所事事
Chihuahua-head motherfucker, man, sitting up there,
还告诉别人自己有多忙
always want to tell somebody what to damn do.
他难道都是和傻子吹牛
He gonna sit there and talk the fool?
娘的  我血压又升高了
Ooh, my blood pressure's high, motherfucker.
不要让这个混蛋气成这样
Don't let this motherfucker get you like this.
又怎么啦
What!
别叫
Stay!
首先  我要明确声明并记录在案
First of all, I clearly want to state this for the record.
我发现这种分配方式太卑鄙了  伙计
And I find this arrangement we got,man, despicable.
但我是弗洛伊德・亨德森  一个老演员
But I'm Floyd Henderson.I'm a trouper.
你知道我会不惜一切代价
And you know I'd do any doggone thing, man,
让这个乐队重返乐坛  伙计
to see this group get back on its feet,
因为你知道我是就是那种人
'cause you know that's the type of motherfucker I am.
但是  同时
But in the meantime,
我要回我一晚上600美元的宾馆了
'm going back to my $600-a-night hotel room,
去洗个舒服的泡泡浴
and I'm gonna have me a nice hot bubble bath
洗掉这一身从你住的黑屋里
to wash some of this filth and dirt and grime
染上的污垢和晦气
from this black fucking hole you live in.
然后再吃上一顿肥美多汁
Then I'm having me a nice, juicy-ass steak, oh, yeah,
和你屁股一样大的牛排
the size of your motherfucking back.
再然后冲个澡刮刮胡须
Then I'm gonna take me a shit shower and shave.
早上六点钟我会到这里
And I'll be here at 6 a. m.
接你去该死的机场
To take you to the motherfucking airport.
-听清楚了  -我不坐飞机
- You got me? - I don't fly.
且我早上8点起床
And I get up at 8.
等我表弟从州监狱出来
My cousin out the penitentiary,
我就让他宰了这混蛋
I'm gonna have him kill this motherfucker!
他妈的跟我说话没大没小
Man talk to me like I'm a motherfucking kid.
我可不是三岁小孩
I ain't no motherfucking kid.
每次我们一起上路
Every time we... we start on the road,
他就开始说同样的废话
he starts in saying the same shit.
喂  谁给我拿午饭
Hey! Who's got my lunch?
你是谁
Who are you?
先生  我是菲利浦・纽曼
I'm Phillip Newman, sir,
新来的实习生  你大约
the new intern. You hired me,
20分钟前雇了我
like, 20 minutes ago.
查克斯・纽曼是我叔叔
Chuckles Newman's my uncle.
-是他告诉你...  -住嘴
- He's the one that told you...- Stop talking.
-遵命  -我已经给了你一份工作
- Very good. - I already got a job for you.
好吗  看看那个
Okay? Bing, bang, boom.Look at that.
对  亨德斯和海因兹  马库斯以前的和声
Yeah. Henderson and Hinds,Marcus' old backup singers,
对悼念什么的一无所知
are being real dickheads about this tribute thing...
天啊  亨德森和海因兹  正拳组合
Oh, my God! Henderson and Hinds!The Real Deal.
他们是唯一一支在单集《灵魂列车》中
They're the only band that got to play three songs
演唱三首插曲的乐队
on a sing episode of Soul Train.
唐・科尼利厄斯当时在场  我还录下来了
Don Cornelius was there as a witness,and I got it on VHS.
他们来这儿不是干这个  好吗
They don't do that here. All right?
-是的  先生  -这是唱片公司
- Yes, sir.  - This is a record label,
不是歌迷俱乐部
not a fan club.
我要那两个老家伙周六到这里
I want those two old fucks there on Saturday,
现在派你去办这件事
and I want you to make that happen.
明白了吗
Got it?
正拳组合要复出  谁也无法阻挡
The Real Deal is back,and they not gonna stop us now.
该死的
Ohh! Shit.
那他妈的是什么  伙计
What the fuck is that, man?
枪啊
This is a gun.
没它就无法穿过三K党的地盘
I never travel through Klan country without one.
-你介意吗  -当然
- You got a problem with that, pops?  - Yeah,
我对那很有意见  伙计
I got a problem with that, man.
上次我看到枪的时候
The last time I saw that gun,
你正指着我  要打我
you were pointing at me,and you were shooting it.
听好了  弗洛伊德  我们不是两个老朋友
Listen here, Floyd.We ain't two old friends
在某个周日驾车去做什么
out for some Sunday drive
缅怀往事的旅游  懂吗
down Memory Lane. All right?
事实上  我一看见你就来气
Fact is, I can hardly stand the sight of your ass,
所以你就不要惹我
so you best not to provoke me.
惹了又怎样
Or what's gonna happen?
从这里到我们目的地之间
There's a lot of empty road
有很多空荡荡的路
between here and where we trying to go.
在那里如果一个黑鬼消失了
Where a nigger could disappear
也不会有人想他
and where nobody'd miss his black ass.
让我看看那支枪
Well, let me see that gun.
让我看看
Let me see it!
小心点啊  傻瓜
Be careful, fool.
你以为我不会拿枪吗  伙计
You don't think I know how to hold a gun, man?
我可是美国步枪射击运动协会的一员
I'm a member of the NRA, man.
在哪...怎么...老天啊
Where's... Now, what's... God damn it!
该死
Oh! Shit!
见鬼
Damn it.
开走  开走  该死的  开走
Drive! Drive! God damn it, drive!
救命
Help me!
抓住方向盘  蠢货
Grab the wheel, fool!
-小心  -现在拐弯  拐啊
- Look out!  - Now, turn! Turn!
你他妈的什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you!
不要在车里开枪
Don't shoot no gun in a car!
你说...保险栓没拉上吗
You said... The safety wasn't on there.
保险栓个屁
Safety, my ass!
保险栓没有
Safety wasn't...
NRA
NRA!
黑人迟钝协会
Negro Retards' Association!
真他妈的蠢货
Dumb motherfucker.
亚利桑那州  旗杆镇
距阿波罗演出还有4天
仅此一晚  千载难逢  正拳组合
那是什么鬼东西
What the fuck is that?
致  意
R-E-S-P-E-C-T.
好久没有在霓虹灯上看到我们的名字了
Been a long time since we saw our name in lights.
我们的名字怎么在霓虹灯上
What our name doing up in lights?
我们周末要在阿波罗剧场演出
We're at the Apollo Theater this weekend.
我们有30多年没上过舞台了
We ain't been on stage in over 30 years.
现在  最不应该做的事情
Now, the last thing you want to do
就是在这里傻站着  是不是
is stink up the joint. Am I right?
所以我准备了一些热身演唱
And I got us free dinner to boot.
伙计  我还留着这些衣服真是走运
Man, we sure are lucky I kept these threads.
看我们多帅啊
Do we look good!
希望那纽扣不会迸出去伤到人
Better hope that button don't pop off and kill nobody.
天啊  裤子这么紧希望不会挤爆我的蛋蛋
God damn, I wish these pants weren't squeezing my nuts so tight.
也许会帮你唱出高音
Maybe it'll help you hit those high notes.
我根本不需要帮助就能唱出高音
I don't need help hitting the high notes.
-是啊  走着瞧  -走着瞧
- Yeah, right. We'll see. - We'll see.
哈哈  撑爆了
Ha ha! Busting out.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
今晚旗杆镇汽车旅馆
tonight, the Flagstaff Motor Inn
隆重推荐30年来
is proud to present to you back onstage
首次重返舞台
for the first time in nearly three decades
唱出令人难忘的悦耳灵魂之声的
the unforgettable sweet soul sounds of...
正拳组合
The Real Deal!
是不是每次
Don't you ever
伤心
Be sad
偎在我身边
Lean on me
度过艰难时光
When times are bad
当那时来临
When the day comes
而你沉没在
And you are down
烦恼之河
In a river of trouble
好像就要窒息
And are about to drown
只需坚持
Just hold on
我来了
I'm coming
坚持住
Hold on
我来了
I'm coming
马上就到
On my way
亲爱的
Your lover
如果你冷
When you be cold
我为你挡风
I'll be your cover
不必担心
Don't have to worry
我在这里
'Cause I'm here
无需召唤
No need to summon me there
我在这里
'Cause I'm here
坚持住
Hold on
我来了
I'm coming
只需坚持
Just hold on
我来了
I'm coming
只需坚持
Just hold on
我来了
I'm coming
听我说  召唤我
Look here. Reach out to me
来得到满足
for some satisfaction.
你知道  弗洛伊德  她要做的
You know, Floyd, all she got to do
是召唤我
Is call my name
来得到回应
For quick reaction
路  路  你没事吧  没事吧
Lou, Lou, you all right? You all right?
我喘不上气来了
I can't breathe!
路易斯
Louis.
继续唱  继续唱
Keep going. Keep going.
我喘不上气来
I can't breathe.
女士们  先生们  请原谅我们
Ladies and gentlemen,please forgive us
这个技术性失误
for this technical difficulty.
我的眼睛  伙计
Fucking eye, man!
对不起  伙计  裤子太紧了
I'm sorry, man. I got on these tight slacks!
我会起诉你这个胖猪的
Well, then, I'll sue your fat ass!
你起诉个鸟啊
You sue these nuts.
-去啊  滚吧  -上帝啊
- Go on, get on outta here. - Jesus!
我们从头开始
Take it from the top.
我们怎么从头开始啊
How are we gonna take it from the top?
-我可以从头唱了  伙计  -你连呼吸都困难
- I'm rewed up to go, man,- You can't hardly breathe.
-你可能需要做个胸透  -我没事
- You may need a chest X-ray.  - I'm good!
在座的有医生吗
Is there a doctor in the house?
我爱你  黛比
I love you, Debbie.
滚远点  蠢货
Get off me, Ernest T!
路  路  路  冷静  伙计
Lou. Lou. Lou. Calm down, man.
不用等到12点再离开了  伙计
Ain't but 12 motherfuckers out here, man.
这儿还有观众
It's still a audience!
就算只有两三个仍然是观众
I don't care if it's two or three.It's a audience.
这就是我说的
That's what I'm talking about.
你的态度坏了事
Your attitude is fd up.
以前也是这样搞砸的
Same thing that messed us up back in the day.
不是  你知道我们怎么搞砸的吗
No. You know what fucked our shit up back in the day?
不  我不知道
No. I don't know.
你他妈当然知道
Oh, you know goddamn well
我们以前到底怎么搞砸的
what fucked our shit up back in the day.
-我知道吗  -是的  你当然知道
- Oh, I do, huh?  - Yes, you do!
我们过去搞砸了
What fucked our shit up back in the day
是因为你搞了我的女人
was you sticking your johnson in my woman!
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我是弗洛伊德・亨德森
I'm Floyd Henderson.
这个白痴是路易斯・海因兹
This fool is Louis Hinds.
我们是正拳组合  是真的
We are The Real Deal,and that's for real.
感谢你们今晚大驾光临
I want to thank you for being a super audience here tonight.
混蛋
Motherfucker.
对不起伤到你了  黛比  回来吧
I'm sorry I hit you, Debbie. Come back.
你他妈的闭嘴  不然我就敲晕你
Shut the fuck up,or I'll knock your dick in the dirt.
该死的醉鬼
Drunk son of a bitch.
开心
Happy
路易斯  我们是谈谈昨晚的事
Hey, Louis, are we gonna talk about last night,
还是继续怄气
or we just gonna let it fester?
好吧  我是有点迟钝  行了吧
All right. Well, I was a little rusty, okay?
说你迟钝都是轻的
That's a insult to rust, ain't it?
那你呢  混蛋
Well, what about you, motherfucker?
昨晚上你好像被水泥卡住了似的
Last night, look like you were stuck in cement.
路易斯  我做过髋关节置换手术
I had a hip replacement, Louis.
那你应多付100美元
Well, you should've paid a hundred more dollars
换一个豪华点  有点节奏感的型号
and got the deluxe model with some rhythm in it.
就因为你换的那个破髋关节
'Cause that motherfucker you got,
-它不好使  -算你对  伙计
- it ain't working.- Oh, that's fine, man.
但是我们要谈的不是这个
But that's not what we talking about.
我是说奥黛特
I'm talking about Odetta.
路易斯  如果我们之间
Louis, if I thought there was still
-仍然有问题...  -你干了
- gonna be a problem between us...- You went
不该干的事情
where you shouldn't have gone,
就是这么回事
period!
现在  这烂事还
Now, there's some shit
余臭未消
that's just etched in stone.
最重要的是
First and foremost is
朋友妻  不可欺
thou shall not dig for diamonds in another brother's mine!
胡扯  伙计  你自己也有责任
Bullshit, man. You gotta take some responsibility here.
你以为她不知道
You think she didn't know, man,
你吸烟
about all of your smoking
酗酒  和吸毒
and drinking and drugs
还有睡别的女人  她知道
and other women? She knew.
她跑过来告诉我  "我的男人
She came running to me telling, "My man
路易斯做这  路易斯做那  抱抱我  弗洛伊德"
Louis did this. Louis did that.Hold me, Floyd. "
那好  睡了她不打紧
All right, well, getting the pussy is one thing.
-你也不必和她结婚吧  -什么
- You ain't had to marry her.- What?
你就是个只会脱裤子的蠢货
You'd have to be a zip-down fool
让她从你手指尖溜走了  伙计
to let her slide through your fingers, man.
好吧  如果我是蠢货  你也是
All right, well, if I'm a fool, then you are, too.
你以为我不知道  她也伤了我的心
You think I don't know that? She hurt my heart, too.
很好  这真是他妈的少得可怜的安慰
Good!That's a poor motherfucking comfort.
但是  不管怎么说  也是个安慰
But it's comfort, nonetheless.
每晚我都告诉你
Every night I'm telling
只要在这里  你就会快乐
Every time you're here, you're making
那你在奥黛特之后又结过几次婚
Well, how many times did you say you was married after Odetta?
四次
Four.
我和一个叫埃斯特尔的女孩儿结婚
I married this girl named Estelle
想忘掉奥黛特
to get over Odetta.
后来又和亨丽埃塔结婚
Then I married Henrietta.
她不适合我
She wasn't no good for me.
后来又和乔瑟芬结婚
Then I married Josephine.
她当然也不适合我  因为后来她遇见了卡尔
She definitely wasn't no good for me because she met Carl.
好  那是第三个
All right. That's three.
谁是幸运的第四个呢
Who was lucky number four?
她叫康斯薇洛
Her name was Consuelo.
她离开我回古巴了
She left me and went back to Cuba.
哈哈  人们还真愿意回古巴
Ha ha ha!People actually go back to Cuba?
她说她宁愿余生待在
She said she'd rather spend the rest of her life
独裁国家也不愿意再跟我多待一个晚上
under that dictatorship than spend another night with me.
你呢  你为什么不结婚
How 'bout you? How come you never got married?
我本来可以在菲律宾的马尼拉
I almost hooked up with this girl down in the Philippines,
搭上一女孩儿的
in Manila.
但是  我不会说
But, uh, I couldn't learn to speak
塔加路族语  她唯一会的英语就是
Tagalog, and only English she knew
花两美元我就让你爽个够
was, "Me love you long time for two dollar. "
在奥黛特之后我就不擅长谈恋爱
Yeah, I wasn't no good at relationships after Odetta.
你有她的消息吗
You ever hear from her?
谁  那个菲律宾女孩儿
Who, Mai Mai?
不是  奥黛特
No. Odetta.
没有  伙计
Oh. No, man.
我有过她的消息  伙计
I heard from her, man.
就在圣诞节的时候
It was sometime around Christmas.
她住在塔尔萨  你知道吗
You know, in that place she was living in Tulsa. You know?
妈的  啪  啪  啪  啪  啪
Fuck it.Pow, pow, pow, pow, pow.
你在干什么
What you doing?
-我看到一个歹徒  -你为什么不把枪口朝上
- I saw a coyote. - Whyn't you put that thing up
省得伤到人  伙计
before somebody get hurt, man?
你怎么老觉得我不会拿
How come you think I don't know how to handle
-这玩意  伙计  -认为
- no damn piece, man? - Think?
是知道
I know.
是吗
Yeah?
好吧  过来和我练练  路易斯
Yeah, come fuck with me now, Louis.
来啊  你以为我窝囊吗
Come on. You think I'm soft, huh?
来啊  我会打爆你这个黑鬼
Yeah.I'll bust one in your ass.
弗洛伊德  你再胡闹
Floyd, you keep fucking around,
我会把枪一直插到你的屁股
I'm gonna stick that gun so far up your ass,
你每次说话都会觉得有火药味
you gonna taste gunpowder every time you talk.
-让我...  -该死
- Well, let me...  - Shit!
见鬼
God damn it!
路易斯  我发誓  这是意外
Louis, that was a accident. I swear.
我出汗了  手潮
I'm sweating. My hand's wet.
你没事吧
You all right?
你不冷吧  你热吗
You warm? You hot?
你头晕吗  是不是有些眩晕
You dizzy? You light-headed?
路易斯 伙计
Louis,
我保证我从来都没想过要伤害你
I swear I would never want to hurt you, man.
我想过杀了你  但我从来都不想伤害你
I thought about killing you,but I'd never want to hurt you.
好啦  为表我们对马库斯・胡克斯无尽的怀念
All right.In our continuing tribute to Marcus Hooks,
让我们在下一首歌里从头回忆
we're reaching all the way back in this next song.
路  是我们的歌  伙计
Lou. That's us, man.
-听着  -马库斯・胡克斯和正拳组合
- Listen.  -... Martin Hooks and The Real Deal.
1969年榜上排名第三的歌曲《我是你的玩偶》
Number 3 in 1969...  "I'm Your puppet. "
拉拉绳
Pull the string
我就向你眨眨眼
And I'll wink at you
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
我会逗你笑
I'll do funny things
如果你想要
If you want me to
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
来啊  路
Come on, Lou.
我得替他说句公道话  这混蛋还真会唱歌
I'll say this for him...  that motherfucker could sing.
公认的  公认的  快来  帮帮忙  和我一起
No doubt. No doubt.  Come on, help me... help me out.
-第二段  -第二段
- Second verse.  - Second?
"拉拉绳"  "亲吻"
"Pull my strings. " Kiss.
...你的玩偶
...your puppet
-什么  -你准备好了吗
- What...  - You ready?
1  2  3
1, 2, 3.
开始
Hit it.
牵牵另一条绳
Pull another string
我就会吻你的双唇
...ing, and I'll kiss your lips
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
踏脚
Tap.
只要敲敲响指
Snap your fingers
我就做几个后空翻
And I'll turn you some flips
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
-伙计  我的胯骨太疼了  -后撤步
- Man, my hip hurt like anything.  - Drop step.
后撤步  你知道我现在做不了
Drop step?  You know I can't do that right now.
你来吧  路
Go, Lou.
很流畅  就这么做  路易
Oh, sweet. Do it, Louie.
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
-哦  是的  我就是  -再来一遍
- Oh, yes, I am  - One more time.
-该你了  弗洛伊德  -我是你的玩偶
- There you go, Floyd.  - I'm your puppet
来吧
Oh! Come on now.
知道  我跟上了
Yeah, I got it now.
跟上了
I got it.
我是你的玩偶
I'm your puppet
接下来你给我们预订了哪里
So where'd you book us next?
就这
This is it?
得克萨斯州  阿马里洛市
距阿波罗演出还有3天
来啊  孩子们
Come on, children
全部凑过来
And gather around
让你们看看
Want y'all to see
我们在下蹲
We're putting down
这事情  谁都能办到
It's a thing everybody can do
来啊  孩子们
So come on, children
一起来摇摆
Do the boogie, too
摇摆没什么难
Boogie ain't nothing
只要弯弯腰
But gettin' down
摇摆没什么难
Boogie ain't nothing
只要弯弯腰
But gettin' down
我为你摇摆
I got to boogie for you
弗洛伊德・亨德森
Floyd Henderson
怎么啦
What is it?
一起来摇摆
Boogie on down
路易斯・海因兹
Louis Hinds
一起来摇摆
Boogie on down
跟着乐队
Listen to the band
我们一起摇摆
We'll make it through
让我们  一起摇摆
All we got is the boogie, too
我为你摇摆
I got to boogie for you
宝贝  你怎么样  想为我摇摆吗
Hey, you, what you got, baby? You got to boogie for me?
来吧  开始
Come on, now.
来吧  要摇摆
Come on, fiddler.
我知道你们想掌控舞台
I knew you were gonna try to take over.
看看他
Look at him.
继续  路
Go on, Lou.
摇摆没什么难
Boogie ain't nothing
只要弯弯腰
But gettin' down
摇摆没什么难
Boogie ain't nothing
只要弯弯腰
But gettin' down
摇摆没什么难  只要弯弯腰
Boogie ain't nothing but getting down
摇摆没什么难
Boogie ain't nothing
只要弯弯腰
But getting down
我为你摇摆
I got to boogie for you
我就是想要摆
I got nothing but boogie
只想为你摇摆
Nothing but boogie for you
我就是想摇摆
I got nothing but boogie
只想为你摇摆
Nothing but boogie for you
摇摆  摇摆  摇摆  摇摆
Boogie, boogie, boogie, boogie
我为你摇摆
I got to boogie for you
有爱共享  宝贝
Share the love, baby.
你刚在台上做了招牌动作  对吧
You know you pulled the Al Green up there, right?
我没有  路  别提那个
No, I didn't, Lou. Don't start that...
我们刚刚下台
We barely got offstage
你就屁颠屁颠的跑回去了
when you ran your ass back out there.
要不要返场观众说了算
Look, an encore is at the audience's discretion.
你应该等他们要求再这么做
You're supposed to wait till they ask for it.
-你知道他们想要返场  -我不关心他们想不想
- You know they wanted it.  - I don't care what they wanted.
你的行为太不专业了
That shit was unprofessional.
伙计
Man...
噢
Say,
我记起为什么我喜欢公路旅行啦
I'm starting to remember why I love the road so much.
就是这个
Yeah.
如果我的直觉是正确的
If my instincts serve me right,
你今晚得给自己另开个房间了
you're about to find yourself another room tonight.
你知道那些蓝色小药丸会让你失明  对吧
You know those little blue pills make you go blind, right?
你要是持续勃起  可别喊我救命
Don't call me when you get that four-hour erection.
来吧  小宝贝
Hey, now, baby girl.
来吧  来吧
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
给我吧
Yeah, give it to me.
小药丸给我力量吧
Those little pills, give me strength.
一点就够了
A little strength.
今晚一定让你爽死
I'm going to fuck your brains out.
天啊  你真重
Oh! Oh, you're heavy.
怎么了  宝贝
what's wrong, baby?
没什么
Nothing.
我只是  我...
I just, uh, you know, I...
我从来没和像你这样的人做过
I just never been with someone like you before.
传说都是真的  但是让我告诉你
It's true what they say.  But let me tell you something.
弗洛伊德・亨德森很好很温柔
Floyd Henderson gonna be nice and gentle.
你的第一个黑男人
Your first taste of dark meat
会让你欲仙欲死  相信我
gonna be smooth and sweet, trust me.
我不是说这个
No, I didn't mean that.
我只是
It's just, uh, you know,
从来没和像你这么老的人做过
I've never been with someone so old.
老
Old?
你他妈也不是什么小女生
You ain't no teen queen your damn self.
别这样  老婆子  过来  宝贝
Come on, mama. Come here, baby.
宝贝  宝贝  听着
Baby, baby. Look here.
让我们用上积攒了几十年的性经验
Let's take our decades of sexual experience
在这个探索与狂喜之夜
and combine them for one night
尽情结合  怎么样
of exploration and bliss, can we do that?
我不会让你失望的
I won't disappoint you.
好吧
All right.
这就是我所说的
That's what I'm talking about.
我要吃你的奶
I want to suck one of them titties.
真的  我有东西让你看
Oh, yeah? Well, I got something to show you.
我全身发热  忍不住要搞我自己
I'm so hot, I'm about to fuck myself.
使劲吻我
Bite my lip off.
哎呀
Oh. Look!
来吧  我忍不住了  宝贝
Oh, shoot, I'm leaking, girl.
今晚我得大干一场
Tonight I ain't got no control like that no more.
希望你不会介意毛太多
Now, I hope you don't mind a little hair.
宝贝  60年代我就性觉醒了
Baby, I found my sexual awakening in the '60s.
我最喜欢又硬又多毛茸茸
Nothing I like better than a big old fluffy...
见鬼  娘们儿
Damn, girl.
你的阴毛可真是茂盛
That's a whole bunch of hair you got down there.
是吧  我把它称作自然景观
Yeah, I call it the natural look.
你那是有什么毛病吗
You sick?
我知道是多了一些
I know it's big.
你得剃掉点
You need a pick.
你想让我先刮一刮吗
You want me to shave it?
我们没时间也没工具去干那活儿
We ain't got the time or apparatus for that type of job.
好吧  忽略这个问题
Okay, disregard.
看看谁来吃饭了
Look who's coming to dinner.
正是时候  对吧
Right on time, ain't it?
我绝对是个硬汉
They call me Mr. Tibbs.
你知道接下来我要做什么吗
You know what I'm gonna do for you?
你准备做什么
What you fixing to do?
你曾有过丝绒滑过的感觉吗
You ever had a velveteen rub?
丝绒滑过
A velveteen rub.
别用奶酪  可以吗
Ain't... Ain't no cheese involved, is there?
因为我乳糖过敏
Because I'm lactose intolerant.
来吧
Oh, yeah.
你想掐死我的小弟弟吗
You're choking my chicken!
昨晚一定和那个大胸女
That's quite a show you got going
上演了一场好戏吧  猛男
under the big top there, Sparky.
搞的我不得不在半夜
I had to take another one of them damn pills
又吃了一次那该死的药
in the middle of the night, man.
那个女人总是难以满足  我简直精疲力尽
This woman insatiable, man. I'm shooting dust.
弗洛伊德
Oh, Floyd.
宝贝  我在这
I'm right here, baby.
你准备好了再干一场了吗
You ready for some more?
是的  来吧
Yeah, come here.
过来
Come here.
还有什么话说  小子
Think about that, boy.
我的小种马在这里哪
There's my stallion.
-我想要你  -你想要我吗
- I missed you. - Oh, you missed me?
你得让这里透透气
Mmm. You need a little air on this thing.
你这个坏孩子
Oh, you bad boy.
该死的
God damn.
你喜欢这样吗
You like that, huh?
我是你的小猫咪
I'm your little kitty cat.
是纯真吗
Chastity?
妈妈
Mama?
你这个小荡妇
You little whore.
你自己不也一样
You're one to talk.
你跟他搞得时候也把假牙拿出来了吗
Oh, did you take out your teeth for him?
注意点和你妈说话的方式
You watch how you talk to your mama.
拜托  你没资格教育我
Please, you can't talk to me like that.
你又不是我老子
You're not my daddy.
说的好  那么谁是你老子
That's right, who's your daddy?
-你是我老子  -你的大JJ老子
- You're my daddy. - Your big daddy.
洛莎莉  你在房间里吗
Rosalee, are you in there?
事实上  我老子在门口
Actually, that's my daddy.
老妈  你想什么呢
What are you thinking, Mama?
你毁了这一切
You ruined everything.
-我恨你  -你这个乳臭未干小骚货
- I hate you.  - You little brat.
你这个肮脏的...好吧  我爱你
You're a dirty...All right, I love you.
要常给我打电话
Call me a lot of times.
老妈  你哪根筋不对
Mama, what is wrong with you?
我再重申一遍  你是个荡妇
I renounce you. You're a whore.
我是荡妇
I'm a whore?
你和那个黑鬼让我们全家蒙羞
You just shamed the whole family, you and the black man.
荡妇
Whoa!
真是太有趣了
Whoo! That was fun.
快来  牵起我的手
So come, take me by the hand
一同离开这片烦恼之地
We'll leave this troubled land
我知道我们可以
I know we can
我会下地狱的  伙计
I'll be damned, man.
那俩婊子偷了我们的钱  伙计
Them broads stole our money, man.
但那是她们应得的
but they earned it.
是我  伙计  弗洛伊德・亨德森
Yeah, man. It's Floyd Henderson, man.
我们出了点情况
We got a situation.
怎么了
What's the problem?
我的前搭档
Well, my ex-partner,
就是那个堕落鬼
the degenerate that he is, man,
招了几个野妓女  把我们洗劫一空
got some trailer trash hos, man, rip us off.
天啊  太糟糕了
Oh, wow, I'm sorry to hear that.
有什么我能帮忙的吗
Is there anything I can do?
是的  你能帮我们  我们需要钱
Yeah, there's something you can do. We need money.
如果没钱
If we don't get no money,
我们就去不了阿波罗
we ain't gonna make it to the Apollo.
我不清楚这么做的程序是什么
I'm not sure what the procedure for that would be.
我的意思是说要经过层层批准
I mean, there's just a lot of red tape here.
你知道的
You know, uh...
我得问过再和你联系
I'm going to have to get back to you.
-快去问  然后马上和我联系  -亨德森先生
- You do that. Get back with me now. - Mr. Henderson...
据我所知
We ain't gonna get very far on ten gallons of gas,
10加仑的汽油可支走不了多远
I can tell you that.
我知道哪能搞到钱
I know where we can get some money.
我知道怎么样搞到钱
I know how to get some money.
塔尔萨  100公里
这不是爱吗  这不是爱吗
Ain't no love, ain't no love
正如你给我的爱
Like my baby's love
让我不再孤独
Ain't no lonely days
Ain't no lonely
见鬼  这到底是什么...
Ooh, shit. What the hell is...
因为我找到一个女孩...
'Cause I ain't never, never found me a girl
该死  不  你不能这么干
Oh, hell, no. You didn't.
不  我能
Yes, I did.
这般爱我
To love me like
喂  喂  你脑子出问题了
Hey, hey, you're...  What is wrong with you?
别那样抓我衣服
Don't be grabbing on me like that now.
如果你敢按门铃
I will knock your ass out before
我就揍扁你
I let you go ring that doorbell.
来吧  老兄  打我啊  来啊
Come on, get up on me, man. Come on.
你真想找揍吗
You really want this? Huh?
来吧  该死的
Come on... Oh! God damn.
-伙计  算了  -怎么了
- Oh, man. Come on...  - What?
你这是怎么了  怎么了
What's wrong, what?
我胸口疼  伙计
I got a pain in my chest, man.
够了  伙计  别耍我了
Come on, man. Stop fucking with me.
我看起来像是在耍你吗
Look like I'm fucking with you, man?
拜托  伙计  帮我个忙
Come on, man, do me a favor.
把我的心脏病药从包里拿出来
Get my heart medicine out of my bag.
-你有心脏病药  -快点  瞧我这副样子
- You got some heart med...  - Oh! Come on, look.
快点  伙计  快点
Come on, man. Hurry up, man.
坚持住  老兄
Hold on, man!
该死  你这的药
God damn, you got enough stuff in here
足够开个药店了
to start a drug store!
这瓶子上写的是什么
What it say on the bottle?
傻瓜  混蛋
Sucker, motherfucker.
我要干掉你
I'm gonna get your ass for this.
愿意奉陪
I'll leave the light on for you.
什么事  哥们儿
What up, dawg?
我们是  奥黛特的朋友
We're friends of, uh, Odetta's.
-奥黛塔  -对  她在吗
- Odetta?  - Yeah, is she in?
她不在  伙计
No, she ain't here, man.
她什么时候回来
Is she coming back?
说真的  估计她不会回来了
Seriously doubt it.
除非我们准备被僵尸攻击什么的
Not unless we fitting to have a zombie attack or some shit.
怎么啦  傅满楚
What's up, Fu Manchu?
-克里奥  -什么事
- Cleo!  - Yeah?
给我出来
Get your ass out here!
有俩黑鬼找你妈
Two old niggers looking for your mama.
进来吧 你们把热气都放出去了
Come on in, man. You're letting the heat out.
妈妈
Mama?
外面很冷
Cold outside.
你们关节炎会发作的
Your arthritis gonna kick up.
谁啊
Who's that?
不知道
I don't know.
你们是
Yeah?
你好  小姐
Uh, how you doing, ma'am?
我是弗洛伊德・亨德森  这位是...
My name is Floyd Henderson. This is my...
我认识你们
I know who you are.
估计你们没听说葬礼的事吧
Guess you didn't hear about the funeral.
葬礼  奥黛特
Funeral? Odetta...
她什么时候过世的
When did she pass?
圣诞节后她就病了
Well, she got sick right after Christmas.
之后  病情急剧恶化
After that, it went pretty fast.
什么风把你们吹来了
So why'd you come to see her?
她欠你们钱还是怎么着
What, she owe you money or something?
-没有  -我们正好在附近
- Oh, no.  - We just in the neighborhood.
克里奥  腊肠放哪里了
Cleo, I can't find the bologna!
我马上过去
I'll be there in a minute!
快点
Hurry up!
我妈在世的话会知道你们来过
Well, if my mama wasn't dead, I'd tell her you stopped by.
克里奥
Cleo!
-稍等一下  -克  里  奥
- Just hold on a second. - C-L-E-O!
-你到底要什么啊  -抱歉...
- What the hell you want? - I'm sorry...
都告诉你了来这是个馊主意
I told you this was a bad idea to come here.
拜托  伙计  别这么想
Come on, man. Don't go there.
我们走吧  好吧
Let's just go, okay?
你猜她多大了
How old you think she is?
27  28
27, 28?
我不知道  我也不在乎她多大了  走吧
I don't know how old she is, and I don't care. Let's go.
别紧张  我来看看
Chillax, let me see something.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
弗洛伊德  你到底找什么呢
Floyd, what the hell are you looking for?
该死
Damn it.
我只是确认一下自己的怀疑
I'm just confirming a suspicion.
就是要做这个
That's all I'm doing.
1981年9月14日  搞定
September 14, 1981. Bingo.
真的就假不了  对吧
It kind of works itself out, don't it?
快放回去
Put it back.
听着
Listen.
伙计  奥黛特在1980年
Odetta left me, man,
感恩节那天离开我
Thanksgiving Day, man, 1980.
-所以呢  -自己动脑子算算  混蛋
- So? - So you do the math, motherfucker.
算什么  黑鬼  拜托
Do the math? Nigga, please...
你听到没
Oh, shit. You hear that?
听到什么
Hear what?
听  那边传来的低音和声
Listen, that bass line, right there.
真他妈见鬼
Son of a bitch.
莱斯特是我  弄臣也是我
Oh, my name is Lester, the Court Jester
黑鬼们说唱让人作呕
All you other rap niggas done messed up
我来教你们做小丑
I take you to school a semester
让法院把你们带走
Take you to court and sequester
法官和陪审都是我
I'm judge and the jury
东家小李  抓狂挥老拳
Bruce Lee, Fists of Fury.
我是莱斯特  你还想抽我
You want to whip me, the L-E-S-T-E-R
抓住妞的腰
Grab my girl by the waist
抽了妞的脸
Slap my girl in the face
老妈一死  我就占她屋
When my mama died, I moved inside her crib
莱斯  莱斯
Hey, hey. Les, Les.
伙计  你们在这儿干嘛
Hey, man, what you doing in here?
我们在做音乐
We're here trying to make some music.
这就是你们做的音乐
That what y'all doing?
我怎么看不出来
I don't see no musicians.
听着  你知道是谁唱的低音和声
Listen, you know who played the base line
就你刚才唱的那段所谓歌词时用的
on that stuff you got running under those so-called lyrics?
正是此人
My man, right there.
说得没错
Yeah, right, man.
他也不是什么音乐人
He ain't no damn instrumentator.
大莱  看这个  伙计  是他们
Hey, yo, Big L, check it out, man. It's them, man.
他们说的没错
They ain't bullshitting.
我来看看
Let me see this here.
正拳组合
The Real Deal, huh?
要是就说你们是胡扯呢
Hey, I mean, so what if we jacked your shit, man? Huh?
好艺术家借鉴别人
Good artists borrow,
伟大艺术家剽窃别人  伙计
great artists steal, man.
-知道谁说的吗  -派卜罗・毕加索
- You know who said that? - Pablo Picasso.
但文学家认为出自T・S・艾略特
But literary scholars sometimes like to attribute it to T.S. Eliot.
不  没艾略特小姐什么事  伙计
Hell, no. It wasn't no damn Missy Elliot, man.
出自贝贝组合
No, man, it was Bay Bay and them.
贝贝  没错
Bay Bay, yup.
这就是贝贝  毫无疑问  贝贝组合
That was Bay Bay, for sure, hey, Bay Bay.
听着
Look, man.
知道吗  对不起
You know what? I'm sorry.
未经许可我不该用你们的音乐合成新曲
I shouldn't have sampled your music without permission.
我们何不一起做首歌
Why don't we all do a song together?
歌名就叫"去你妈的低音和声"
A song called "Fuck You and Your Bass Line. "
这就是我的感受
That's what I feel about it.
就这么认为你们那该死的低音和唱
Here what I think about your damn bassline.
亨德森和海因兹
Henderson and Hinds!
拿走这堆破烂
Take that shit with you.
黄脸蛋的混帐
Gold-faced motherfucker.
我就是一流氓  咋地
I made that shit gangster, that's what I did.
我来教教你  伙计
Let me tell you something, man, you...
别吵了
Hey! Stop it!
Stop it!
这可是我家  听到了
Hey! This is my house. You hear me?
我不想你们这么疯折腾
I don't need this shit right now.
在哥们面前你说我疯折腾
You gonna talk to me crazy in front of my boys?
你还说什么啊  给我闭嘴
Why you still talking? Shut the fuck up!
佩佩和吱吱
Pay-Pay and Zig-Zig,
我们走  伙计
let's dip, man.
再见  老黑鬼
Bye, old niggers.
好好用我的设备
Feel free to utilize my facilities while you're here
再造一次辉煌
to make yourself another hit.
艾克打败蒂娜后你们就没有红过
I know you ain't had a hit since Ike hit Tina.
给我滚出去
Get out of here.
从烤架上
Get the fuck
他妈的滚开
Out my grill
趁你还活着
'Fore you get killed
莱斯特是我  弄臣也是我
My name is Lester the Court Jester.
真他妈是个无耻的混蛋
What a disrespectful son of a bitch.
-别再说了  -别说了
- Just lay off. - Just lay off?
我知道你妈想让你学好
I know your mama taught you better.
奥黛特会让他屁滚尿流
Odetta would've whooped his damn ass.
你他妈怎么知道我妈会怎么做
The fuck you know about what my mama would've done.
她得癌症要死的时候你在这里
Were you here when she was dying of that cancer?
不在吧  但莱斯特在  你知道个屁
I don't think so. I think Lester was. The hell you know.
说的对  我屁事不知
You're right. I don't know nothing.
对  他一无所知
That's right, he don't know shit.
说得没错
No, he don't.
我要去换衣服做晚饭
Now I'm going to go change and get dinner started
你们会留下吧
because you guys are staying, right?
不  我们要赶路
Oh, no. We need to hit the road.
对  小姐  我们留下
Yes, ma'am. We are staying.
那好
Okay, then.
老妈肯定期望这样
Hell, it's what Mama would've wanted.
没错  是奥黛特的孩子
Oh, yeah. That's Odetta's child, all right.
客房我为你们准备了
Okay, I put some sheets on the bed
铺上新床单
In the guest room for you guys.
多谢
Thank you.
卡拉・托马斯的歌  对吧
That's Carla Thomas, right?
没错  你妈最喜欢的
Sure is. Your mother's favorite.
你们怎么就发了一张专辑
So how come you guys only put out that one album?
当我们没争你妈的时候
Well, when we wasn't fighting over your mother,
唱片卖得不好
we had a problem in our record sales.
我们没卖出去多少
Yeah, as in we didn't sell any.
对
Okay.
没准会红起来
Well, you'd never know it wasn't a hit,
大家都像妈妈一样喜欢
as much as Mama played it.
都要100度啦  你还穿着皮夹克
About 100 degrees, and you got a leather jacket on.
好好享受  山姆
Appreciate it, Sam.
她说过
She said,
跟你们在一起的日子
being on the road with y'all
是她一生最快乐的时光
was some of the best times of her life.
美好时光  美好时光啊
Oh, good days. Good days.
真希望能见识一下
I wish I could've seen that.
这么说  干吗不跟我们去孟斐斯
Say, why don't you come to Memphis with us?
-孟斐斯  -是啊
- Memphis? - Yeah.
-什么  -我们有个演出
- What? - We got a gig.
弗洛伊德  弗洛伊德
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Floyd, Floyd.
人家有自己的生活
The girl got a life.
她可没空
She ain't got time to be ripping,
跟两个老黑鬼在路上颠簸
running up and down the road with two old niggers.
为什么不能
Why not?
孟斐斯很好玩  我们在孟斐斯总是很开心
Memphis is fun. We always have fun in Memphis.
你会喜欢的  相信我
You'll enjoy it. Trust me.
好玩  我像是有时间玩的人吗
Fun? Look like I got time for fun?
路易斯
Hey, Louis.
克里奥告诉我
You know, Cleo was telling me
奥黛特从没跟她谈起过她父亲
that Odetta never told her nothing about her father,
名字都没提过
not even his name.
但她提过他是个音乐家
But she did say he was a musician.
你没跟那女孩瞎说八道吧
You ain't said nothing stupid to the girl, have you?
比如
Like what?
Oh, like, uh,
克里奥  我是你爸爸
Cleo, you know, I'm your daddy.
我还要再搞清楚状况
Well, I'm still feeling out the situation.
那你他妈干吗说
What the fuck was that
你应该跟我们去孟斐斯啊
that "You ought to come to Memphis with us" shit?
那样说  会种下祸根
Now that, right there, that's a recipe for disaster.
路易斯  路易斯  我知道你肯定很难过
Louis, Louis, I know this ain't easy for you.
但是我从没想过我有孩子
But I never thought I'd have a child.
现在我也开始生生不息了
Now I'm part of this big old circle called life.
弗洛伊德・亨德森也许真有子孙后代
A piece of Floyd Henderson, man, might be here to live on,
也许会永传万代
and maybe forever.
再不闭嘴睡觉
If you don't shut up and go to sleep,
混蛋弗洛伊德・亨德森
A big piece of Floyd Henderson ass
可能明天就醒不了了
Might not wake up in the morning.
路易斯  路易斯
Oh, Louis, Louis.
我很佩服你
I respect the fact that you want
能用怒火掩盖痛苦
to cloak your pain with your anger.
晚安
Good night.
这他妈是什么
Oh, hey! What the fuck is that?
怎么了
What's wrong?
你又吃了那壮阳药了
You been taking them dick pills again?
是降低胆固醇的药  是吃了
I though it was my cholesterol meds, I swear I did.
你也不能沉迷于那玩意啊
You can't be spooning with a motherfucker with that!
你什么毛病啊
What's wrong with you?
-我  -下作的混蛋
- Uh, I... - Nasty son of a bitch!
给我点盖的  我去地上睡
Give me some covers. I'm gonna sleep on the floor.
混蛋
Shit.
去吧  地上睡吧
Go on, then. Sleep on the floor.
谁也不喜欢你  路易斯
Nobody wants you, Louis.
我也不喜欢娘娘腔
I don't like boy pussy no way.
疼死你的背
I hope your back hurt like a motherfucker.
起码背疼比被戳屁眼好
Better my back than my asshole.
恶心  抡死你个狗娘养的
Nasty... I'll beat your motherfucking...
我在监狱呆那么多年
All them years I spent in prison,
没人敢对我这样
ain't nobody roll up on me like that.
我正想问你
I was going to ask you about that.
你真该惭愧得要死
You ought to be ashamed of your goddamn self,
恶心的混蛋
nasty son of a bitch.
好似我从未有
Like I never had
当我伤心时
When I'm feeling bad
快点来给我安慰
Come on and comfort me
哦  宝贝  你知道路
Oh, baby, you know the way
我告诉过你  该如何爱我
I showed you how to love me right
今夜来安慰我
So comfort me tonight
快点来给我安慰  宝贝
Come on and comfort me, honey
你知道路  宝贝
You know the way, baby
因为我指给你看过
'Cause I showed you right
我需要  我需要
I want it, I want it
为何不来
Why don't you
给我安慰
Comfort me?
弗洛伊德
Floyd!
亨德森先生  亨德森先生
Mr. Henderson. Mr. Henderson?
不  我是路易斯
No, this is Louis.
海因兹先生
Mr. Hinds.
我是FC管理部的菲利浦・纽曼
It's Phillip Newman of FC Management.
你好吗  伙计  我是你的超级歌迷
How are you, man? I'm a huge fan.
那又怎样
So?
所以
So...
我想我已经解决了你们现金问题  伙计
I think I've solved your cash flow problems, my man.
我从父母的账户
I've withdrawn $10,000
取了1万美元
from my old parents' savings account
帮你们渡过难关
to tide you over until things get sorted out.
你刚才说你是谁
Who'd you say you was again?
菲利普
Phillip.
当你关在里面的时候
I wrote you letters when the man had you
我给你写信了  知道吗
locked down in the pen, you know?
我知道你是无辜的  那样是不公平的
I know you're innocent. Shit ain't right.
好啦  菲利普  这样
Okay, Phillip, um, look here.
我们要去孟斐斯
We're on our way to Memphis.
你5点到皮博迪酒店喷泉
Um, why don't you meet us
和我们会合
at, um, the fountain at Peabody Hotel, 5 clock.
孟斐斯  好的
Memphis. All right!
我比饿狼还饿
I'm hungrier than a mo...
你在这啊  姑娘  决定了吗
There you are, girl. You make up your mind?
跟不跟我们去孟斐斯
You want to go to Memphis with us, or not?
怎么决定的
What you gonna do?
怎么回事
What happened?
没事  没事
Nothing. Nothing happened.
没事
Nothing happened.
不要
No.
让他去吧
Let him get his whupping.
你干吗打她
Why you hit her?
你能怎么着
The hell you gonna do about it, man?
我可是拿着枪的  伙计
I'm the nigger with the gun, man.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
过来
Come on.
你个白化病痞子  抬起屁股跟我走
Get your albino Ike Turner ass up, uh-huh.
过来
Come on.
好吧  好吧  见鬼
Aah! Okay! Oh, shit! Aah!
我的头发  伙计
My follicles, man!
看着她说"很抱歉我打你了"
Look her in the eye and say "I'm sorry I hit you,
我再也不会打你了
and I'm never gonna put my hands on you again. "
-我的错  宝贝  我不该   -照我刚才的说
- My bad, baby. I ain't... - Say what I told you to say!
很抱歉我打你了  我再也不会打你了
I'm sorry I hit you. I ain't never gonna do it again.
现在  说抱歉用我的低音和声混音
Now, say you're sorry for sampling my bass line
抱歉踩坏了我搭档的唱片
and for stomping on my partner's record.
抱歉用你的低音和声混音
I'm sorry for sampling your bass line
-抱歉踩坏了你们正拳组合的唱片  -好了
- and stomping on your Real Deal record. - Okay.
现在我们要上路  需要点油费
Now, we taking a road trip, and we need some gas money.
我没钱  伙计
I ain't got no money, man!
能帮我们不  我看到你卖那些东西了
Can you help us? I saw you out there selling that shit.
那是香烟  不是毒品  伙计  我没有拿到...
It's weed, it ain't crack man! I ain't got...
-交出钱来  -好吧  好吧
- Give me the money! - Okay, okay.
钱在我短裤
There's money in my shorts...
没人会伸手到你短裤里  自己掏出来
Ain't nobody reaching in your drawers, get it out!
好的  好的
Okay, okay.
我绕在鸡鸡上了  伙计
I got to reach around my meat, man.
-给  -拿着
- Here. - Take it.
拿着
Take it.
天  我头发好疼
Oh, damn. My hair hurts.
拿着  伙计
Take it, man! Aah!
你要弄断我的胳膊了
Ow! You're breaking my arm!
安静
Oh, hush.
这只是小小的中国擒拿手
That's just a little Chinese submission hold.
我弄断你的胳膊应该是这个感觉
This is what it feels like when I break your arm.
-见鬼  -弄断他胳膊
- Shit! - Break his arm.
混蛋
Oh, bastard!
我遇到过像你一样的混蛋  莱斯特
I know motherfuckers like you, Lester.
以前在放风场上天天能看到
Used to see them in the yard every day.
你最好祈求别坐牢
You'd better hope you don't never go inside
因为你就是当婊子的料
because you, you straight up bitch material.
那我的车怎么办
What about my car, man?
还问你的车
What about your car?
混蛋
Oh, shit.
我都没穿外衣
I ain't got no clothes on.
真是混蛋
This is bullshit.
那怎样  你赶紧穿着内裤
So what? You run around with your drawers
抬屁股滚远点
hanging off your ass anyway.
我会杀了你的
I wasn't really gonna shoot you!
快他妈给我滚
Get the fuck out of here.
我才是拿着枪的
See, I'm the nigger with the gun now.
你最好希望我胳膊别好
You better hope my arm don't get better.
我要学空手道打你个稀巴烂
I'm gonna learn karate and kick your ass!
去你妈的
Fuck you!
你出手干涉
It was a good thing you stepped in
绝对正确  搭档
when you did what you did, partner,
要是我逮到他
because if I'd have got a piece of him,
我要整死他  你知道的
I'd have fucked his shit up entirely, and you know that.
来吧
Come on.
跟他打我太老了
I'm too old to be tussling with the motherf...
我会一枪毙了他
I'd have shot him. I'd have popped...
我六七岁的时候  打架
I'm six, seven years older. I'd have, like, tussled...
欢迎回到灵魂之旅
Welcome back to the Soul Patrol.
我是艾萨克・赫斯
I'm Isaac Hayes.
我要大声说出他们的名字
I want to give a shout-out
弗洛伊德・亨德森和路易斯・海因兹  正拳组合
to Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds, The Real Deal.
他们今夜重返孟斐斯
They're back in Memphis tonight
在灵魂之屋演出
performing at the House of Soul.
1号火车开走了
Train number 1 is gone
欢迎回家  伙计们
Welcome back home, fellas.
2号火车开走了
Train number 2 is gone
3号火车也开走了
Train number 3 is been gone
我还要等你多久
How long must I wait for you
仔细看清楚
Look out with it.
这就是孟斐斯火车
It's the Memphis train
奥芬剧院
The Orpheum Theatre!
我们就在那里演出
Our show's up in there.
我要等你多久
How long must I wait for you?
孟菲斯火车
The Memphis train
让我再来试一次
Let me try it one more time
天啊
Oh, my God.
亨德森先生  海因兹先生
Mr. Henderson, Mr. Hinds,
让我先
let me just start off by saying...
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了
What's up?
菲利浦  今晚我们要在灵魂之家演出
Phillip, tonight we're playing at the House of Soul.
一定要来啊  宝贝
Make sure you be there, baby.
一定去
Right on.
你好  欢迎来皮博迪
Hello. Welcome to the Peabody.
您需要什么
How can I help you?
宝贝  给我3间
You can help me by giving me
你们这最好的套间
three of your best doggone suites, baby.
好的  很高兴能为您服务
Well, it'll be my pleasure to assist you today.
请出示您的身份证
May I see some identification, please?
好的
Okay.
给你
Right there.
去死  路易斯
Go to hell, Louis.
亨德森先生
Mr. Henderson?
是的
It is I.
麻烦您稍等一下
Will you excuse me for just a minute, please?
好的
Okay.
-对不起  亨德森先生  -亨德森
- Ahh, I-I'm sorry, Mr. Henderson, - Henderson.
我们不能让您住在这儿
We're unable to accommodate you.
也许我们可以为您推荐其它旅馆
Perhaps we could recommend another hotel.
为什么  伙计  我在孟菲斯
For what, man? I'm in Memphis.
我要住在皮博迪
I want to stay at the Peabody.
当然  先生  您之前住过这儿
Yes, sir, I understand you've stayed with us before,
可这就是问题所在
and apparently, that's the problem.
似乎上次您住这儿的时候
It seems that the last time you stayed here...
准确说是1978年3月12日
March 12, 1978, to be exact...
您办了个聚会  期间  您住的房间
you hosted a party, during which the room
以及酒店的几个其他地方
and several other areas of the hotel
遭到了大面积的破坏
sustained extensive damage.
我怎么不记得这回事儿
I don't recollect nothing like that.
我想是斯莱和布特西
I think that's the night Sly and Bootsy
带吞火魔术师来的那个晚上
came by with the fire-eater.
是玩蛇的那个人
Is that the one with the snake?
就是他
That's the one.
也许你可以用路易斯・海因兹的名字
Perhaps you could put those rooms
订房看看
in the name of Louis Hinds.
没错
Yeah, perhaps.
路易斯・海因兹  我们试试看
Louis Hinds, we'll try that.
对不起  琳达  让你看到这些了
I'm sorry you had to see that, Linda.
怎么啦  我看看
What's on there? Let me see that shit.
我要看看到底怎么了
I want to see what's on there.
我要四个房间  先生
I need four rooms, Don.
你们最好的客房
Your best available.
伙计们
Oh, hey, guys.
裁缝给了我几件今晚的演出服
Your tailor gave me several choices for tonight.
他说他大约7点半到
He said he's going to stop by around 7:30.
那是什么
What the fuck?
你跑去打劫花花公子商场购物了
Did you catch the sale over at the Build-A-Pimp?
你喜欢这个吗  很棒吧
You like that? It's fly, huh?
这样穿很时髦
It's a get-down, get-down. It's live. It's funky.
我想应该找几个保姆
And I think I'm going to get some poonanny.
说实话
To be honest with you,
自从电视开播《老友记》  我就没泡过妞
I haven't been laid since Friends was on television.
今晚我要好好享受
So this is my night.
你确定他不是你的孩子吗
You sure that ain't one of your children?
今晚你会唱得很棒的
You gonna sing real nice tonight.
女歌手是谁
Who's the girl singer?
噢  天  看啊  伙计
Oh, my goodness! Look at here! Oh, man.
你好  路易斯  很高兴见到你
Hello, Louis. Good to see you.
你好吗  伙计
You good, man?
你看起来不错
Hey, good-looking.
克劳德特  你好吗  小妞儿
Claudette. How you doing, girl?
我知道你不会还在对
I know you still ain't upset
在巴尔的摩所发生的事难过
about what happened in Baltimore that...
你犯什么毛病  娘们儿
Oh! What's wrong with you, woman?
直接下地狱去吧  弗洛伊德・亨德森
You going straight to hell, Floyd Henderson.
你笑什么
What you laughing at?
-也想来一下吗  -不
- You want some, too? - No.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
去你妈的  去你妈的
Fuck you, fuck you
这下我们没有女歌手了
Now we have no girl singer.
我们找人代替不就行了
We just got to find a replacement, that's all.
时间不够了
It's too late.
克里奥
Cleo.
你会唱我们所有的歌  对吧
You know all our songs, right?
别介意我直说  伙计
Ho ho ho. No offense, man,
我不和不入流的票友一起演出
but I'm not playing with no rank amateur.
别这样  沃夫曼  她不是不入流的票友
Come on, Wolfman, this ain't no rank amateur, man.
伙计  她是奥黛特・惠特菲尔德的女儿
This Odetta Whitfield's daughter, man.
还没出名而以
Ain't got to recognize.
真是的  那我们开始吧  宝贝
Shit. Let's roll, then, baby.
她会唱歌吧
She can sing, can't she?
我们开始
Here we go.
如果音乐让你起舞
If music makes you move
你就尽情享受
You can really groove
享受
Groove on
如果你真的想热恋
If you feel like you want to make love
就在满天繁星下
under the stars above
热恋
Love on
如果你真的有话要说
If there's something that you wanna say
却又找不到出路
And talking is the hard way
说唱
Rap on
因为无论是什么  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
你就应该勇往直前
You got to do your thing
如果你真的想呐喊
If you feel like you want to scream
如果这是你怒气在释放
If that's your way you let off steam
呐喊
Scream on
如果你真的想歌唱
If you feel like you want to sing
因为唱歌就是你所想
'Cause singing is your thing
歌唱
Sing on
如果你想整夜都热恋
If you want to make love all night
因为你感觉很棒
'Cause you feel it's right
-很棒  -噢  没错
- Right on  - Oh, yeah, girl.
很棒
Right on
因为无论是什么  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
你就应该勇往直前
You got to do your thing
我是这乐队的  是的  这是一支梦幻般的乐队
I'm with the band. Yeah, it's a dream.
是的  就是一支梦幻般的乐队
Yeah, it's a... it's a total dream.
我弹哈姆菲卡
I play the harmuffica.
我帮你看着位子
I'll save you a seat.
因为无论是什么  只要你想做
'Cause whatever you want to do
太棒啦  宝贝儿
Yeah, baby, oh
你就应该勇往直前
You got to do your thing
今晚是我一生中最疯狂的一晚
This is the most insane night of my life.
艾萨克想让我去他的工作室
You know Isaac wants to put me in his studio?
他说他有一首歌非常适合我唱
He says he's got a song that'd be perfect for me.
噢  真的吗
Oh, he does, does he?
别这样  不是你想的那样
Uh... Come on, now. It ain't like that.
总会是那样的
Oh, it's always like that,
就像电影里演的
like movies.
好吧  我会小心点的
Well, I'll be careful.
只是担心你而已  没别的
Just trying to look out for you, that's all.
谢谢你们为我做的一切
Thanks, guys, for everything.
你就应该勇往直前
You got to do your thing, hey
再见
See you later.
如果你真的想热恋
If you feel like making love
因为这是你所想
'Cause that's your thing
很棒
Right on
伙计  这不是正拳组合的车吗
Man, ain't that the Real Deal car?
那当然  朋友  你是歌迷
Sure is, homie. You a fan?
是的  我是超级歌迷
Hell, yeah. I'm a big fan.
你知道他们在哪儿吗
You know where they at?
因为我要找他们诉诉苦
'Cause I need to holler at 'em.
说实话我是他们的经纪人
Actually, I'm their manager.
真的  他们的经纪人
Really? Their manager?
等一下
Hold on a minute.
弗洛伊德
Oh, hi, Floyd.
进来吧  看看这地方
Come on in. Check this place out.
我会习惯上这里的
I could get used to this.
我肯定你会的
I'll bet you could.
喝一杯吧
Let me get you a drink.
好的  给我来一杯
Yeah, I'll take one.
等等  先别去倒酒
But hold on, before you do that,
有件事想和你说
there's something I want to say to you.
是让你吃惊的事情
It's been a blast connecting with you.
我想你该知道这件事
I want you to know that.
你真好
That's sweet of you.
如果你有什么需要
And if you need anything,
比如钱什么的
like money or something like that,
直接告诉我
don't you hesitate to call me now.
不是因为钱能弥补
Not that money gonna make up for
我们没有在一起的日子
the lost time between us
或是别的什么
or nothing like that.
逝去的日子
Lost time?
你要理解
You have to understand,
奥黛特从来没有告诉过我有关你的事
Odetta never told me nothing about you.
如果我一开始就知道有你
Had I known about you from the beginning,
我会在你身边的
I'd have been here from the start.
-弗洛伊德  -她从没向我提过你的事
- Floyd... - She never said nothing to me about you.
弗洛伊德  你不是我父亲
You're not my father, Floyd.
你没在听我说
You're not listening.
你的事  什么  你说什么
See, the thing you... what's that? Say what?
你不是我父亲
You're not my father.
我不是
I- I'm not?
你不是
No.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我父亲知道我
Because he knows who I am
或者他曾经知道我
Or he did.
我是说  就我所知
I mean, for all I know,
他可能已经死了
he could be dead.
每过一段时间   他会寄钱给我
I get a little money from him every once in a while.
是他许多年前设立的保密委托
It's a blind trust he set up years ago.
钱从他的音乐版税来
Something to do with his music royalties.
音乐版税
Music royalties?
你上了我老婆  你这混账东西
You knocked up my wife, motherfucker.
你先从我这偷走她的
Ooh. You stole her from me first.
你发什么疯
What is wrong with you?
你失去了你的...
You lost your...
你没和克里奥说吧
You didn't tell Cleo, did you?
没有  我没告诉她
No, I didn't tell her.
虽然我应该告诉她
I should've told her, though.
你一定笑翻了吧
I'll bet you laughing your ass off, wasn't you?
四处散布说我才是那女孩的父亲
Going around, talking about I'm the girl's daddy
还有生生不息之类的废话
and big round circle of life, all that bullshit.
笑吧  笑吧  混账东西
Giggle, giggle, motherfucker.
就那么一点点
Well, just a little bit.
弗洛伊德
Floyd...
听着  弗洛伊德
Look, Floyd...
弗洛伊德  放下  放下
Floyd, put it down. Put it down!
兄弟  别这样
Dawg, come on!
住手  不然你会受伤的
You need to quit before you get hurt.
听着  弗洛伊德
Look, Floyd,
我不是故意的  行了吧
I didn't mean for it to happen, all right?
你知道她是什么人
You know how she was.
拉我一把
Come here.
好了  伙计  别再犯傻了
Come on, man. Stop acting a fool.
你没事吧
You all right?
混蛋  别再犯傻了
Aw, shit. Quit acting a fool!
去你大爷的
Fucking dad!
你他妈的又什么不对了
What the fuck is wrong with you?
暂停
Time out.
伙计  尝到我那一拳的利害了吧
Still got a little pop in your punch there, partner.
尝尝这一拳  混账
Pop this, motherfucker!
混蛋
Shit. Ugh.
你这个混账东西居然打我的蛋蛋
You dirty motherfucker, hitting me in the nuts.
混蛋
Ooh! Shit.
路易斯  不可能一直是你扁我
Louis, you just can't keep whooping on my ass.
我也是他妈的男子汉  宝贝
I'm a motherfucking man, baby.
我也是他妈的男子汉
I'm a motherfucking man.
路易斯  你怎么能不去看你女儿呢
Louis, how come you won't see your own daughter?
混蛋  我想去看她
Oh, motherfucker, I wanted to see her,
但是
but, you know...
是时机  过一段时间以后
It's time... After a while,
就变得  就变得难以承受
you know, it's just... it's just too much.
奥黛特为什么不告诉她
Why didn't O tell her?
伙计  奥黛特为什么不告诉她
Why didn't Odetta tell her, man?
让她说什么
What was she going to tell her, huh?
说她父亲是个又酗酒又吸毒的人渣
That her daddy was a alcoholic dopehead convict
说她父亲一事无成
that fucked up everything he touched, hmm?
不行  不行
No, no.
没有我她过得更好
She was better off without me.
混蛋
Oh, shit.
不管怎样  一切都太晚了
Anyhow, it's too late now.
遇见她是个错误
It was a mistake getting to know her.
-路  -怎么啦
- Lou... - What?
你怎么了  发病了
What is wrong with you? You having a seizure?
怎么啦  怎么啦
What? What?
克里奥
Oh. Cleo.
-克里奥  等等  -让一让
- Cleo, wait. Ow! - Excuse me.
该死的  等等
God damn it. Wait!
听我说
Let me talk to... ow!
走开  该死的
Move, God damn it!
回来  克里奥
Come here, Cleo!
报警
Call the police.
你  白小子
Hey, yo, white boy.
你真的在音乐圈工作
You really in the music business?
干吗  你有带子需要混音
Why, do you have a mix tape?
你他妈的给我闭嘴  白小子
Shut the fuck up, white boy!
还有别再流那么多汗
And stop sweating so goddamn much.
你闻起来像腊肉
You smell like bacon.
而我吃素
And I'm a Muslim on Saturdays.
你哪根筋不对
Fucking wrong with you, huh?
明明是白人却留非洲人的头发
How you white and got a afro?
一点儿也不帅
That ain't cool.
该死的  我头疼
Damn, my head hurt!
克里奥出来了  克里奥出来了
Hey, there go Cleo. There go Cleo.
出租车
Taxi.
我的宝贝儿就在那里
There go my baby, right there.
她去哪儿
Where she going?
去哪儿  宝贝
Where to, honey?
克里奥
Cleo!
该死
Oh, hell, yeah.
那个像史奴比的老混蛋也出来了
There go that old Snoop Dogg-looking motherfucker.
正拳乐队
Real Deal,
他们就要完蛋了
hey fitting to be real dead!
我来了  老家伙
I'm coming for you, old man!
莱斯  给这些老混蛋点厉害瞧瞧  伙计
Hey, yo, Les, let them old motherfuckers have it, man.
-我去了  -去吧  黑鬼
- I'm going for it. - Go for it, nigger.
搞定这些混蛋
Get them motherfuckers.
停下  伙计
Come on, now.
你知道只有我才能开这辆车
You know I'm the only who drive the Mothership, man.
看莱斯特怎么把这两个混蛋干掉
Watch this shit with Lester about to kill on these motherfuckers.
这是我们的生存方式  我们就这么做
That's how we live, we do it like that.
路易斯
Louis!
我回来了
I'm back!
他有枪
Gun!
糟糕  混账莱斯特弄砸了
Oh, shit! Motherfucking Lester got fucked up!
该死的
God damn!
我要赶紧离开这糟糕的...
I'm out of this motherfucker...
-莱斯特怎么办  老兄  -去他妈的莱斯特
- What about Lester, man? - Fuck Lester.
就是  去他妈的莱斯特
Yeah, fuck Lester!
你都不认识莱塞特  伙计
You don't even know Lester, man.
你干吗撞我  伙计
Why you run over me, man!
你们这两个老杂种
You old dirty bastard!
老非洲
Old Jim Brown, Fred Williamson,
欺软怕硬的混蛋
two-the-hard-way motherfuckers!
我发誓要杀了你们
I'll kill you, I swear...
混蛋
Aah! Shit!
伙计  至少让我干掉你一次
Let me kill you one time at least, man!
你把车子弄坏了
You done fucked up the Mothership.
我应该一刀刺进你的喉咙
I ought to stab you in your throat.
去你妈的
Fuck you! Aah!
你听见了吗
You hear that?
崩了这个混蛋  路易斯
Shoot that motherfucker, Louis.
举起手来
Get your hands up!
我举不起来  伙计  我胳膊打着绷带
I can't, nigger. My arm's in a brace.
放下武器  快点
Drop the weapon now! Come on!
我是第一次进这种地方
This is my first time ever being in here.
安静点
Quiet, please.
摩菲尔监狱  距离演唱会还有一 天
这个肮脏的地方
This filthy-ass motherfucking place,
弄的我浑身发痒
man, got me itching.
看守
Yo, turnkey!
快点放我出去
Come on and let me out of this motherfucker!
你应该面对现实
You might want to wrap your mind around the fact
现实就是我们要错过演出了
that we're gonna miss that show.
你他妈说什么  伙计
Fuck you talking about, man?
明晚我们一定要到纽约
We gotta be in New York tomorrow night.
不包括我
Uh-uh. Not me.
我受够了  精疲力竭
I've had enough. I'm done.
什么  你要丢下我一个人  路易斯
What, you're walking out on me, Louis?
听着  佛洛德  在你到我家之前
Look, Floyd, I was doing just fine
我还好好的
before you showed up at my door.
你应该感谢我
That's the thanks I get
把你从破老鼠洞里救出来
for pulling you out of that fucking rat hole.
你本来应该坐在那儿
You was just sitting up in there,
坐在那儿等死
just sitting there waiting to die.
拜托  黑鬼
Negro, please.
你比我好不到哪去
You ain't no different from me,
你侄子把你这老年痴呆赶走
Especially since your nephew put your senile ass out to pasture
还抢了你生意
and stole your business.
混蛋  路易斯
Fuck you, Louis.
快滚回你的破老鼠洞吧
Crawl back under that damn rock you've been living.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
我自己能搞定
I'll do this shit by my damn self.
看守
Yo! Turnkey!
让我从这个鬼地方出去
Come on and let me out of this motherfucker.
我受够了  我要见律师
I've had enough, man. I want my lawyer.
放松  放松
Relax, relax.
你不需要律师了
You ain't gonna need no lawyer.
目击者证实了你的说辞
Witnesses say your story checks out,
所以  先生  你可以走了
so you, sir, are good to go.
太好了
Yeah.
等等  摇滚小子
Whoa. Hold on there, Chuck Berry.
你可能需要请个律师
You're gonna need a lawyer.
你越过州界违反了假释条款
Seems crossing state lines is in violation of his parole,
更别说持有枪支
Not to mention possession of firearms
和无照驾驶
and driving without a license.
无照
No license?
借一步说话
Step back for a minute.
希望你烂死在这儿
I hope your ass rot up in here,
你他妈的罪有应得
you criminal-bound motherfucker, you.
老子曰  "不欲以静  天下将自定"
As Lao-Tzu says, "Let things flow forward as they may. "
那我就顺其自然了  宝贝
And I'm gonna let it flow, too, baby.
我也给你点亚非后裔哲学  朋友
And I got some Blackanese philosophical shit for your ass, pal.
你能蒙混  但是没法逃脱  路
You get by, Lou, but you don't get away.
黄泥巴掉到裤裆里  不是屎也是屎
You sit in shit, you start to smell like it,
所以自己小心别沾上
so check the crack of your ass.
还有些东西给你
Here's something else for you.
这是她的号码
Here go her number.
给她打电话吧  老爸
Call her... Daddy.
去死吧
Fuck him, man!
我得快点离开这个鬼地方
Let's get on out of this motherfucker.
他啥也不是
He ain't worth two damn flies smashed.
这个黑鬼
Nigger.
我能打个电话吗
Can I make a phone call?
你要丢下我一个人  路易斯
You walking out on me, Louis?
我受够了  精疲力尽
I've had enough. I'm done.
你没事吧  伙计
You all right, man?
是的  是的  我很好
Um, yeah, yeah. I'm all right.
你一点也不好  呼吸都困难
You're not all right. You can't hardly breathe.
你需要做胸部X光检查
You need a chest X-ray.
我不想复出
I ain't trying to make no comeback.
我已经离开  就不想回去
I'm gone, and I want to stay gone.
你应该感谢我
That's the thanks I get
把你从破老鼠洞里救出来
for pulling you out of that rat hole,
坐在那等死
just sitting there waiting to die...
sitting there waiting to die...
- 死  死  - 太晚了
- die, die...  - It's too late.
在座的有医生吗
Is there a doctor in the house?
抓紧时间
Keep it short.
我是克里奥  请留言
It's Cleo. Please leave a message.
克里奥  我是路易斯
Cleo... um, this is, uh, Louis.
路易斯・海因兹
Louis Hinds.
你父亲
Your father.
这么说有点奇怪
Wow, um, feels funny saying that.
我以前从没这么说过
I've, um, I've never said it before.
听着
Listen.
我没别的意思
I didn't mean what I said.
我只是
I was...
奥黛塔是我生命中的最爱
Odetta was the love of my life.
对我来说最糟糕的
The worst thing that ever happened to me
就是失去你们
was losing her and you.
但是你现在这么优秀
But you turned out great.
她把你教育得很好
She did a wonderful job with you.
你妈妈是个了不起的女人
You know your mother was an amazing woman.
我只想告诉你
And I just want you to know
我非常  非常高兴见到你
I'm really, really glad I met you.
我希望我
And I wish I...
好啦
All right.
你他妈的知道自己在干什么吗
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
把你救出监狱
Busting your ass out of jail.
你看我像在干什么
What the fuck does it look like I'm doing?
后退  宅男  把钥匙拿出来
Back up, Red. Get your keys out.
打开牢门  懂吗
Open that cell, okay?
长官  别听他的
Deputy, don't listen to him.
他不会开枪的  至少打不中
He will not shoot you. Not on purpose anyway.
别被他骗了  宅男
Don't let him get you fucked up, Red.
我会毫不犹豫地开枪
I'll kill you disco-dead.
打开牢门  先生
Now open that doggone cell, man.
别抖  否则我也会抖
Stop shaking. If you shake, I'm gonna start shaking.
接下来你知道怎么做
Next thing you know, kapow!
进去
Go on in.
现在把钥匙给他
Now hand him the keys.
快给他
Hand them to him.
-好了吗  -弗洛伊德
- Okay?  - Floyd.
你真的要这么做
You sure you want to do this?
是不是每件事都要跟我争
Does everything gotta be a fucking argument with you?
该死的  快出来
God damn! Come on out of there!
关门  路  锁上
Close the door, Lou. Lock it up.
我是人质
I'm a hostage.
如果你不他妈的闭嘴
You're gonna be a dead hostage
你就将变成死人质
if you don't shut the fuck up.
看这里  宅男
Now look here, Red.
总的来说  我欣赏你
I like you, almost.
打电话给除了老妈以外的人  就是找死
You call anybody outside your mama, kapow.
明白吗
Okay?
咱们走吧
Let's get out of here.
有人跟踪吗  伙计
Anybody following us, man?
目前没有
Not yet.
不过我打赌马上会有
But you can bet your ass they will be.
路  我们得弃车逃跑  伙计
Lou, we gotta dump the Mothership, man.
我们得弃车
We gotta dump it.
你能丢下你的爱车
You'd abandon the Mothership?
从法律上来说我们是逃犯
We're fugitives from the law.
我们的按逃犯的思路考虑问题
We gotta start thinking like it.
逃犯不是我们
We're not fugitives, O.J.
而是你  我是人质
You're a fugitive. I'm a hostage.
这是我的说辞  而且我会坚持
That's my story, and I'm sticking to it.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
看  看  看
Hold, hold, hold, hold, hold, hold.
看那边  伙计
Look at that right there, man.
那不是莱斯特的车吗
Ain't that Lester's car?
混蛋
Motherfuckers.
我们饿了  伙计
We're hungry, man.
来点烤鸡什么的
Come up with some baked chicken or something.
他们又开始了
They're at it again.
该死的  莱斯特的车
Oh, shit! Lester's car!
- 听见了吗  - 什么
- You hear that? - What?
那个
That.
哦  我的天啊  天啊  不
Oh, my God! Oh, God, no! Oh, God...
海因兹先生  亨德森先生
Mr. Hinds. Mr. Henderson.
看见你们太好了
It's so good to see you.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你都不知道  里面有多热
Oh, it was so hot in there. You have no idea.
如果有什么我能帮忙
If there's anything I can get you,
比如来杯拿铁咖啡  我就是为你们服务的
like a latte, I'm here for you guys.
但是我得先去方便一下
But first I really have to pee,
所以我得先跳出去
so I'm just gonna hop on out.
请你能拉我一把
If you could give me a hand out of here.
我被关在这儿
I've been locked in there,
他们还整天开着低音喇叭
and they've had the woofers going all day.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我得去撒尿  如果你不介意
I just have to pee real bad, so if you don't mind.
看见你们太好了
It's so good to see you.
海因兹先生
Oh, Mr. Hinds...
马库斯・胡克斯的遗体
The body of Marcus Hooks
今天早晨抵达肯尼迪机场
arrived at Kennedy Airport earlier this morning,
并受到国王般的迎接
and in a processional befitting a king,
随后将会送到本州的阿波罗剧院
will make its way to the Apollo Theatre,
在那里遗体会安置得
where it will lie in state...
我正在看
I'm watching it right now.
十分妥当
...appropriately enough,
遗体放在一个钢琴形状的棺材里
in a piano-shaped coffin
以便上千名悼念者
for the thousands of mourners gathered
为优秀的灵魂乐先锋送行
to pay tribute to the beloved soul pioneer.
插播  其他相关消息
Meanwhile, in related news,
警方正在全力缉拿
authorities continue the search
弗洛伊德・亨德森和路易斯・海因兹
for Floyd Henderson and Louis Hinds,
他们于今天凌晨越狱
following a daring jailbreak early this morning.
这两个人已经在
The two backup singers were on their way
去往纽约的路上
to New York City
打算出席晚上的悼念仪式
to perform at tonight's tribute
来纪念昔日的伙伴
honoring their one-time partner.
该死
Fucking A!
当前经济不断增长
Local economy is getting a big boost from...
是的  不  不  我明白
Yeah. No, no. L... I understand.
我有电话进来
Uh, that's my other line.
稍后给你回电话  我是丹尼
I'll call you back. This is Danny.
你好  爱普斯坦先生
Hello, Mr. Epstein.
菲利普・纽曼  我上周弄坏了你的订书机
Phillip Newman. I broke your stapler last week.
-没有搞错吧  -在听吗
- Are you kidding me? - Hello?
该死的你在哪
Where the hell are you?
听着  我打电话来是要告诉你
Listen, I called because I just wanted to let you know
一切都很好  都在我们掌控中
that everything's cool, and we're still on target.
我们
We?
你跟亨德森和海因兹在一起吗
You're with Henderson and Hinds?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
虽然他们总是说"混蛋"
They say "motherfucker" a lot,
但他们都是好人
but they're really good guys.
好吧  很好
All right, well, good.
你告诉他们
You can give them this message.
电视网那边刚打电话来  他们不能出席演出
The network just called, and they're off the show.
他们不能这么做
But they can't do that!
哦  是吗  那可是VH1频道
Oh, really? It's VH1.
你看过爱的滋味吗
Have you seen Flava of Love?
他们可以为所欲为
They can pretty much do whatever they want.
还有  你被开除了
And another thing, you're fired.
混蛋  去死吧
Motherfucker! What the fuck?
他怎么说
What'd he say?
他说我被开除了
Uh, he said I'm fired,
还有  还有  你们不能出席活动
and... and, uh, and you're off the show.
你  你说真的  伙计
Are... Are you serious, man?
对不起
I'm so sorry.
根据地图来看
You know, uh, according to the map,
那条路通向高速公路
that road leads to the turnpike.
我们仍有时间完成
I think we've still got time to make it.
完成什么  路易斯
Make what, Louis?
你听见那个混蛋怎么说的
You heard what the motherfucker said!
都结束了
It's over!
去他妈的
Fuck that.
我们说结束才是真的结束了  明白吗
This shit ain't over till we say it's over, all right?
一切都不同了
Things have changed,
我精神上有了新的领悟
and I have achieved a state of mental clarity.
说的太好了
Ain't that a bitch?
你听见那个混蛋的话了吗
You hear what this motherfucker said?
伙计  从我敲你家门开始
Ever since I knocked on your door, man,
你就一直反对我
you've been beating my balls at every fucking turn.
现在突然间有领悟了
Now all of a sudden, you've got a state of clarity.
你的领悟从洛杉矶来的  路
Where was your clarity in L.A., Lou?
你不能只像订匹萨一样
You can't just dial that shit up
打个电话  混蛋
like you calling for a pizza, motherfucker.
一定要深入  干实事
You got to go inside, do the work.
因此  我承认
Consequently, I have a confession.
弗洛伊德  你是对的
Floyd, you were right about me.
我放弃了生命中很多事情
I have given up on a lot of things in my life.
但这次我不想放弃  行吗
But I ain't giving up on this. All right?
来吧  伙计  我们过去几天经历了那么多烂事
Come on, man, we've been through enough shit the last few days.
我们这次也可以挺过去
We can do this.
没人敢阻止我们
And I dare anybody to try to stop us.
出发  混蛋
Let's go, motherfucker.
枪
Shotgun.
坐后面去
Get your ass in the backseat.
无法再阻止我们
Ain't no stoppin' us now
我们踏上征程
We're on the move
曾有许多事让我们停滞
There's been so many things that's held us down
但是现在看来
But now it looks
一切都能克服
Like things are finally coming around
千万别失望  失望
Don't you let nothing, nothing
坚定不移
Stand in your way
我要你倾听  倾听
I want y'all to listen, listen
我说的每个字  每个字
To every word I say, every word I say
无法再阻止我们
Ain't no stopping us now
没有  没有
No, no, no
我们踏上征程
We're on the move
路途奇妙
The movin' groovin'
无法再阻止我们
Ain't no stopping us now
音效和地板放射性监测器都打开  懂吗
Full sound and switch on all the floor monitors, all right?
看那个  那个很管用很敏感
Look at that. That's nice and subtle.
我马上做  音效测试
I'm on it, then. Sound check.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
- 爱普斯坦先生  - 什么事?
- Mr. Epstein. - Yeah?
你在这太好了
Hey, thank God you're here.
天  这怎么可能
Oh, God, this isn't happening.
你在这干什么  我已经开除你了
What are you doing here? I thought I fired you.
我只想告诉你  我不是自己来的
I just wanted to tell you I'm not alone.
你们都疯了
You guys are insane!
很高兴见到你  小爱普
Good to see you, too, Little Ep.
这根本行不通
Yeah, this is never going to happen.
你们一旦被认出就会被逮捕
You'll be arrested the moment the cops spot you.
我们不关心那些
We don't care anything about that.
我们只想唱自己的歌
We just want to do our song.
还有一件事  你有时间吗
Oh, one other thing. You got a few minutes?
有  我占用了全世界的时间
Yeah, I got all the time in the world.
我正在录制一个电视秀
I'm just producing a television show
有很多音乐明星参与
with dozens of huge musical acts
还有17分半钟就开始直播了
that goes live in 171/2 minutes,
但是你知道  拿些咖啡来  我们谈谈
but you know, let's grab some coffee and have a little chit-chat.
他得这病多长时间了
Wow. How long's he got?
不知道
We don't know.
好吧
All right.
我会尽力的  好吧
I'll see what I can do. Okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
女士们  先生们  女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, ladies and gentlemen,
请各位就座
please take your seats.
仪式马上开始
The ceremony will begin shortly.
我去开门
I'll get it.
黑人摩西
The Black Moses.
你怎么样  伙计
How's it going, man?
怎么啦
Hey, what's happening?
你怎么样  宝贝
What's up, baby?
伙计们
Hey, fellas.
怎么啦
Hey, what's happening?
-伙计  -我的伙计
- The man. - My man.
好啦
Okay, all right.
听说你们来了  祝你们好运
Heard you were here. Just wanted to wish you luck.
顺便说一下
Oh, by the way,
我带了个人见你
brought somebody by to see you.
是吗
Oh, is that right?
是的
Yeah.
好了  我们都出去吧
Okay, everybody, let's move on out of here.
快点
Come on.
好了  大家都听见亨德森先生的话了
All right, you heard what Mr. Henderson said.
你先走  小伙子
After you, young man.
好的
Okay.
对不起我选择了逃避
I'm sorry I ran out the way I did.
我才是逃避的人
I'm the one who ran out.
你不需要道歉
There's no need for you to apologize.
能帮你打领带吗
Can I help you with your tie?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
你知道自己在做什么吗
You know what you're doing?
是的  我当然知道
Yeah, I know what I'm doing.
好了
Here you go.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事  帮我拿点水
Yeah. Just some water, please.
该死
Damn!
相机都准备好了
All cameras are on point.
刚加了两个麦克风
We just added two mics.
爱普斯坦先生  快过来一下
Mr. Epstein! You better come quick.
快点  我是认真的
Come on, I'm serious.
快点  情况紧急
Come on! It's important!
好的  帮我照看一下这里
All right. Take care of those.
只有15分钟了  丹尼
15 minutes, Danny.
他突然就病发了
He just collapsed.
我觉得他肯定很痛
I think he's in a lot of pain.
张开手  张开手
Open your hand.Open your hand.
在这里  在这里
Right there, right there.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
坚强点  老兄  坚持住
Be strong, brother.Hang on in there.
现在不是去医院检查的时候
It ain't time for you to check out now.
检查  干嘛
Check out? What?
行了  伙计
Come on, man.
大家都知道是怎么回事
Everybody knows, man.
我阿姨也在用这种该死的药  伙计
My aunt was taking the same doggone pills, man.
她一个星期  疼得又踢又叫
Took her about a week before she wasted away to nothing,
然后就越来越瘦弱直到死去
just kicking and screaming.
我不知道她得什么病死的
I don't know what killed her ass,
但如果她是吃了这种药  那她就有膀胱炎
but if she was taking those,she had a bladder infection.
你说什么
Say what?
蒙古大夫  我有肾结石
Look, Doctor Dumbshit,I got a kidney stone.
虽然在尿尿的时候确实他妈的痛
Hurts like a motherfucker when I pee,
但还不至于要了我的命
but it ain't gonna kill me.
这么说你不是要死啦
So you're not dying?
自从我们呱呱坠地  都注定了会有死的那天
From the first slap and cry,we all start to die.
但我不会死得那么早  绝对不会
But I ain't on no accelerated program,hell, no.
真是天大的笑话
Ain't that about a bitch?
我做了这一切  把你从监狱里劫出来
All that damn hard work,busting your ass out of jail,
但你却还死不了
and you ain't even dying.
我多希望能看你到死的那一刻
I was kinda looking forward to seeing you go.
打扰一下  丹尼  他们两分钟后上台
Excuse me, Danny.They're on in two.
好的  大家都准备好了吗  伙计们
All right. Where we at, guys?
好了  我没事
Okay, I'm good.
犹如麦加圣地一般的阿波罗剧场
The Apollo, the mecca.
唤起了无数的美好回忆  伙计
This brings back memories, man.
我们已经在这表演过多少次了
How many times you think we've performed here?
条子
ooh, five-oh.
50场  真的吗
50, really?
有条子
Five-oh.
快点  跑  跑
Come on. Move, move.
是他们  站住  站住
That's them! Hold it! Hold it!
所有单位注意  所有单位注意
All units report, all units report.
发现嫌疑犯
Suspects have been spotted.
所有单位  秘密拘捕他们  但记住按规章办事
All units, apprehend them quietly and by the book.
路  你认为他们走了吗  伙计
Hey, Lou, do you think they're gone, man?
我又不能透视  蠢货
I don't have X-ray vision, motherfucker!
我怎么会知道
How would I know?
声音小点  路  该死
Lower your voice, Lou.Doggone it, man.
这里太黑了  根本什么都看不到
It's so dark in here you can't see shit.
等等
Hold up.
我看看能不能找到打火机
Let me see if I can reach my lighter.
别在这点打火机  伙计
Don't light no lighter up in here, man.
你想让我们变成烤肉吗
We'll blow up like a barbecue.
等一下
Hold on one minute.
该死的
Shit.
是他妈的马库斯・胡克斯
Marcus motherfucking Hooks.
这里离林伍德大街挺远的吧  混蛋
Long way from Linwood Street, huh,motherfucker?
去他妈的林伍德大街  还有他
Fuck Linwood Street and him.
他利用了我们两个  这你是知道的
He used both of us, and you know it.
别这样  老兄
Come on, man.
他只不过觉得自己是腕儿了就单飞了而已
He just thought he'd be a bigger star going solo.
他做得很对
He was right.
对个屁
No he wasn't.
他只不过不想把钱分成三份罢了
He didn't want to split the money three ways.
看看他那衰样  傻呆呆地坐着
Just look at him, sitting there
脸上还挂着老年痴呆般的笑容
with that old shit-eating grin on his face.
你觉得自己很行  是不是  混蛋
You think you're all that, motherfucker, don't you?
我必须承认  每次只要一想到你
I have to admit, every time I think about you,
我就恨不得想把你掐死
I could just choke the shit out of you!
住手  住手
Stop it, stop it!
弗洛伊德  他没想法  他是死人
Floyd, he ain't thinking shit. He's dead.
看啊  这不是我的表吗
Say, ain't that my watch?
看看  你认为是我偷了那该死的
See? You thought I stole that mother...
我告诉过你这混蛋是一个盗窃狂
I told you this motherfucker was a klepto!
该死  看看那个
Shit, look at that.
真漂亮
That's nice.
也许这个也是偷的
Probably stole that, too.
这混蛋的品位向来不错
Motherfucker always had good taste, though.
这个我留下了
I'm gonna keep this.
路易斯
Hey, Louis.
你觉得如果
You think if, you know...
如果他没有  没有死的话
if he wouldn't have, you know, died,
你觉得我们会再重组吗
you think we would have got back together?
不  当然不
Oh, hell, no.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
我们现在在一起
We are together,
我一直在考虑我们的分配问题
and I've been thinking about our little arrangement.
我们把酬金五五分  怎么样
I'm gonna go ahead and break you off 50/50, all right?
路  你实在是
Wow, Lou, that's...
你实在是太够意思了  伙计
that's real black of you, man.
但是我们其实没有酬金
Because there ain't no money.
你说什么
Say what?
是你自己说的
Well, you said it yourself.
这是个葬礼
It's a funeral.
没人会花钱请你唱歌  伙计
Nobody pays you to sing, man.
那个酬金是你编出来的
You lied about the money?
-是的  -你这个混蛋
- Yeah.- You motherfucker.
但你不能说来这一趟并不值得啊
Hey, you can't say it wasn't worth it.
我是想说不值得
Well, I could say it.
但那是撒谎
But I'd be lying.
我爱你  路
I love you, Lou.
好兄弟
My nigger.
但对于这个混蛋  我忍不住
But this motherfucker,you know, I can't help it.
每一次  我都忍不住想要杀了这个混蛋
Every time,I could just kill this motherfucker!
他离开的原因就是你总是挑剔他
That's why he left, because you was always picking on him.
别跟他较劲了
Stop fucking with him.
他毁了我的幸福
He fucked with my happiness.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我是艾萨克・赫斯
I'm Isaac Hayes.
他们死到哪儿去了  丹尼
Where the fuck are they, Danny?
我亲爱的朋友们  请跟我一起
My good friends, please join me
向我们的兄弟马库斯・胡克斯告别
in saying farewell to brother Marcus Hooks.
是路易斯和弗洛伊德
It's Louis and Floyd!
是正拳组合
It's the Real Deal!
马库斯・胡克斯和正拳组合
Marcus Hooks and the Real Deal,
再度聚首
back together again.
请为他们鼓掌吧
Give them a hand.
为了团聚
Reunited, y'all.
他们将再次合作
They got their shit together.
是的  让我们拭目以待吧
Yes! Let's go!
各就各位  听我的命令行事
Stand by.Move in on my command.
请等等  等等  等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
拜托了  各位警官和探长
Come on, Officer detective person.
求你们  别这样
Please, just, you know, come on.
允许他们唱一首歌  只要一首
Let them sing one song.One little song.
不会出什么乱子的
It's not gonna hurt anybody.
正拳组合
The Real Deal!
好吧  就一首歌
All right. One song.
但最好是好歌
But it better be good.
一首歌  一首好歌
One song. The good one.
胯骨感觉怎么样
How's that hip?
完全准备好了  宝贝
Locked and loaded, baby.
开始吧
Let's do this.
乐队
Band!
我们来一首《公园漫步》
Let's take a walk in the park.
1  2  3  4
1,2,3,4!
当河水开始流淌
When the river gets to rollin'
你为其注入满满灵魂
And then you add a bowlful of soul in
我试着让它尽情奔放
And then I tried to let it all go then
哦  对我来说很简单
Oh, it's easy to me
看看  我如何驾驭节拍
You see, the way I ride the rhythm
看看  我如何只讲实话
You see, the truth is all I can give 'em
而歌词就是取自生活
And the lyrics can come from livin'
哦  耶  哦  对我来说很简单
Oh, yeah, oh, it's easy to me
音乐就来自我的内心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公园
Something like a walking the park
就像漫步在公园一样
It's just a walk in the park
我没听见  其他人在公园
And no one else in here, I heard it
我不知道  是否得偿所愿
I don't know what I've done to deserve it
全心投入没有疑惑
You don't question it while you serve it
这是天赐机缘
Oh, it was given to me
赋予我你的激情
I got something you inherit
我不知道你是否为分享它而生
I don't know that you was born to share it
但是  若想成功  没它不行
And if you shoot,be sure you wear it
哦  这是我的本性流露
Oh, it comes naturally to me
音乐就来自我的内心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公园
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公园一样
It's just a walk in the park
今也你们是否开心
Y'all having a good time out here tonight?
我就是想让你开心
This is what I'm talking about!
你可知公园漫步  伙计
You know about that walk in the park, man?
我当然知道公园漫步
Sure I know about that walk in the park.
-真的  -让你瞧瞧
-You do? -I'll tell you what.
-让他们看看 -开始
- Show them. - Got to get down.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请在阿波罗剧院的舞台上
let's give a big Apollo welcome
热烈欢迎首次在这里表演的
to the stage for the first time,
我的女儿  克里奥・惠特菲尔德小姐
my daughter, Miss Cleo Whitfield!
全力开创一片天地
To make something out of nothin'
这是我们共同志愿
That's what we all got in common
只需紧紧相拥  我就到来
So just hold on tight, I'm comin'
告诉我
Said to me
我就给你可坚持的信仰
I'll give you something you can believe in
今夜我们全身心投入
And then enjoy yourself this evenin'
你肯定不能抽身而去
And don't you dare think about leavin'
跟我一起唱
Sing along with me
音乐就来自我内心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公园
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公园一样
It's just a walk in the park
音乐就来自我内心
Music comes out of my heart
就像漫步在公园
Something like a walk in the park
就像漫步在公园一样
It's just a walk in the park
音乐就来自我内心
Music comes out of my heart
就一首歌
One song.
因在狱中表现良好获得减刑
正拳组合终于正式重返舞台
并且加入一名新主唱
音乐就来自我内心
Music comes out of my heart
我是他们的经纪人
I'm their manager!
就像漫步在公园
Something like a walk in the park
漫步在公园
Walk in the park
就像漫步在公园一样
It's just a walk in the park
Just like a walk in the park
你今晚会唱得很棒
You're gonna sing real nice tonight.
快乐时光要来临
Got that funky time
我能感受到
I can feel it
每当摄像机或者麦克风开启之后
Any time the camera or the mic comes on,
我不会糊弄自己
I don't cheat myself.
这是我在孩提时候学到的第一条原则
That was rule number 1 I was taught as a kid.
当然我肯定也不能糊弄观众
And I definitely can't cheat the audience.
因此每一次做事
So I give 150%
我都会付出150%的努力
every single time that I do anything.
我的生活中也是这样
Even the way I live my life.
我会珍惜每一次糟糕的经历
I just cherish each doggone moment.
再说个黑人牧师的笑话吧  怎么样
A black preacher's something else, ain't it?
你去了教堂以后付不起房租
You can't pay your rent after you come from church.
如果你向牧师要5块钱
And if you ask the preacher for the $5.00,
他这样告诉你  "以神的名义操你妈"
he'll be like, "Fuck you in the name of Jesus. "
我的喜剧不是臆想出来的
My comedy is not fictitious.
我的喜剧必须得来自我的内心
My comedy has to come from my heart.
-查理・陈是个好汉  -好吧  来排练一下
- Charlie Chan was a hell of a man.- All right, let's rehearse.
上完厕所  逛过中国还没洗手
He went through China with his shit in his hand.
五个女人靠墙站
Had five women against the wall.
我敢打赌他把她们全部都干
I betcha five dollars that he fucked them all.
他辛苦地干
He fucked them hard.
他长久地干
He fucked them long.
一直感到弟弟被抽干
He fucked them till his shit got sore.
他去看病  大夫回答
He went to the doctor,and the doctor said,
"对不起  查理  你的弟弟已经不应答"
"Sorry, Charlie, your dick is dead. "
他说  "大夫  大夫  不是真的阿"
He said, "Doctor, Doctor,that can't be true. "
"没错  先生  你的蛋蛋也没气啦"
"Yes, sir, Charlie,your balls are too!"
我的一生都在演出
I've been performing all my life.
因此  对我来说  在观众面前表演
So being in front of an audience
从来都不是问题
has never been a problem for me.
该离开了
It's time to go?
那就走呗
Well, go on, then.
要给观众留下长久的印象
You want to leave a lasting impression on your audience.
这也是我第一次开始表演时
You know, and that's something I was taught, too,
别人教给我的
when I first started.
尽量让观众记住你
Always make them remember you,
或者记住关于你的电影的一些事
or remember something about you and the film.
我要回我600美金一晚上的酒店去了
I'm going back to my $600-a-night hotel room,
来一个  一个泡泡浴什么的
have me a nice-ass, uh,piece of pussy and shit.
是吗
Okay?
停
Cut it.
好的  深呼吸  深呼吸
Okay, just breathe. Breathe.
我还没进去呢
I'm not even in yet.
让我来为你跳舞
I got to boogie for you
我为你摇摆
I got nothin' but boogie
只想为你摇摆
Nothin' but boogie for you
我只想摇摆
I got nothin' but boogie
只想为你摇摆
Nothin' but boogie for you
摇摆  摇摆
Boogie, boogie
我想对你们所有人说声谢谢
I want to say thanks to you all
因为你们成就了我
because you all made me... yeah.
没有你们就没有我的电视秀或者电影
I wouldn't have no TV show or movies.
你们是为了看我才来的
You all was coming to see me,
是你们成就了我
and you all made me...
在查塔努加  路易斯安那  密西西比
Chattanooga, Louisiana, Mississippi.
谢谢你们
So thank you.
我想如果我跟其他很多人一样
I think if I had a few free passes
度过很多的空闲时间
like a lot of people,
我就不会像现在这样成功
I don't think I would be as successful as I have.
我经历的最艰苦的事情
My task here on Earth
就是我必须得比常人更加地努力
is I have to work harder than the average bear.
这看起来很简单  不是吗
It look easy, don't it?
但实际上不是的
But it's not.
谢谢你  甜心  谢谢
Thank you, sweetheart. Thank you.
此片赠与 伯尼・麦克和阿里扎・海耶斯
两位真正的灵魂歌手